Chapter 2: Zimbardo's Methodology Was Flawed, Pt 1

Here's how it is:

Shortly after the story in HPMOR, Harry remains deeply concerned about the fate of the world, despite Moody having made progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital, and Bones apparently grudgingly willing to take his cues on national policy. Although, she's very concerned that they're hiding something about that policy from the others.

Draco is concerned about his future; his father is gone, his family has lost a significant amount of money, and because Harry has been so distant, Draco is convinced Harry's and Lucius' deal (for Draco to become leader of Magical Britain) has fallen through. Draco then finds a secret cache of dark and powerful objects his father had squirreled away, including the diary of one Tom Marvolo Riddle.

Moody is suspicious of Gilderoy Lockhart, McGonagall's new hire for Defense professor. But that's nothing new, and Moody has found no evidence of wrongdoing in spite of putting some effort into investigating him. Moody, Bones, McGonagall, and Hermione are all concerned about Harry's apparent desire to release Voldemort from the ring in order to question him about the mirror and help rescue Dumbledore. Sprout has mysteriously received a gift: the long-lost and apparently cursed Hufflepuff Cup.

"Wow, this place is huge!" Dean exclaimed.

Neville looked embarrassed. Susan elbowed Dean.

"I mean, happy birthday."

"Thanks."

They walked outside to the even larger yard where the party was happening.

Hannah walked over to the group, "Everyone in Hufflepuff missed you after you left Hogwarts last spring. Are you coming back this fall?"

"Yeah, I'll be back. I mean, there's no reason not to, with Voldemort gone (again). There's no way this year will be that crazy or dangerous. We'll lose another defense professor but that will probably be it. I wonder what Harry and Hermione will be doing, though. They've apparently been studying all summer to take their OWLs early."

Theodore shook his head, "I'm betting on multiple deaths and mysterious resurrections. Whatever happens has to top last year."

Tracey laughed, "Of course Harry and Hermione will be back. Can you imagine either of them as Hogwarts dropouts? That would take a confundus charm powerful enough to cover the whole school and last for decades."

"I don't know about that", Ron replied. "I never thought I'd look forward to going back to school, but the underage magic law makes everything else so boring. If I could lose one summer studying and then be able to do magic anywhere and not have to study ever again, that would be bloody brilliant."

Tracey smirked. "You stopped doing magic over the summer? Ha ha."

Ron indignantly demanded, "You've been doing magic this whole time!? How?"

Tracey just pointed at him, still laughing. Neville shrugged and offered, "Longbottom manor is warded against lots of stuff. The ministry can't detect anything within the house unless someone calls aurors through the floo."

"You're lucky", Seamus said. "I had to 'accidentally' switch wands with mom so many times before the aurors stopped responding when she cast spells with it."

Susan frowned, "Yeah. That happened. My aunt says they pretty much ignore reports of underage magic unless either someone does something stupid or a Wizengamot member requests reports on someone. Malfoy and his faction used to prevent their enemies' kids (and muggleborns) from using magic, but the rule didn't really apply to anyone else. This summer, I don't think the DMLE followed up on anything."

"Oh... Then I guess the aurors must have come because of the fire damage."

"Ah", replied everyone else, nodding in understanding.

Ron turned back to Tracey, who had recently stopped laughing, "So what was your brilliant method for not getting caught."

Tracey shrugged, "I'm friends with Susan. Oh, Harry and Hermione are here."

"Hey, Harry", Neville waved him over. "After you pass your OWLs, are you coming back to Hogwarts for classes or are you going to drop out to teach the rest of the world the true meaning of chaos?"

Harry feigned offense, "You don't think I can do both?"

Hermione answered, "Seriously, though, we'll be taking Defense and Herbology with the second years, Transfiguration, Arithmancy, and Divination with the third years, and Potions and Astronomy with the fourth years. We might sit in on a Charms class, but we aren't magically powerful enough to take the fourth year class right now."

"I thought you were taking your OWLs. Why aren't you taking 6th year classes?"

Harry answered, "We scored enough As to be able to vote in the Wizengamot, but there's a huge difference between passing a test and being competent at something. And it's important that we're proficient in most subjects. For example, there are about a dozen charms and a dozen potions that they've rotated through for the bulk of those OWLs for several decades so you don't need to learn much to pass. Professor Sprout was away or busy all summer, so we didn't get any practical Herbology training at all. And for some reason, they don't let anyone test out of Arithmancy; people have to actually go to every lecture. It's annoying because I'm sure I could have passed the NEWT for the math that wizards use. Though, it's great to be done with History forever, with 'forever' defined as 'as long as Binns is still teaching."

While Neville was talking to Harry, the rest of the group had slowly dispersed. Harry expected people to lose interest in conversations about school, but he felt oddly suspicious. He turned around to get an overview of the rest of the party-

"Surprise!", yelled everyone. A banner changed its text from 'Happy Birthday, Neville' to add 'and Harry'.

Harry looked back at Neville and whispered, "you know I'm going to get you back for this, right?"

Neville just smiled and nodded.

Hermione rolled her eyes and shook her head.

Harry walked toward the snacks and drinks table and glancing at the butter-beer tap, he suddenly had a thought. He didn't know exactly what would happen, and if his working hypothesis were correct, it would literally have no effect. But he found himself unable to resist.

A moment later, he returned, handing Hermione a mug and taking a sip from his own.

Some time later, Fred and George ran up to Harry, followed by Ginny.

"We need your help", George began.

"Also, Ginny demanded we introduce her", Fred interjected. "She's your biggest fan but you probably already knew that from that picture in the Prophet."

Ginny looked at Harry and opened her mouth to say something, but apparently forgot her lines. Then she stomped on Fred's foot and chased him as he hopped away while George continued, "The 'entertainment' here is for babies. Children's songs, jokes for little kids."

"Ah", Harry answered. "Did you-"

"Think about the problem for five minutes? Yes. Our best solution was to ask you to snap your fingers."

Harry paused for a second, then solemnly intoned, "By my god-like authority, I command the universe to rain chaos and fun down on this party", then snapped.

That's when a pigeon flew overhead and crapped on Augusta Longbottom.

Madame Longbottom had been standing on the conjured stage, beginning to introduce the group she'd hired when the white liquid hit her shoulder, splashing onto her cheek and dribbling down her robes. About half the children laughed. and a few choked on their drinks. She hastily cast a pair of cleaning charms and concluded the introduction.

The group began playing the music for their first song, amplified through a pair of stones radiating a constant sonorus charm.

Just before the first lyric, the singer tripped, knocking heads with one of the musicians, who fell, instinctively reaching out to break his fall, poking another musician in the eyes.

Then the sonorus-speaker system transfigured into what appeared to be a pair of very small, very deformed dragons, which began roaring, drowning out the sound of children's laughter with an out-of-tune but recognizable version of the song that was being performed.

The performers got up and talked privately for a moment. One walked over to Madame Longbottom, saying "We can't work like this; we'll send you a refund."

A while later, a silvery owl circled over the property once, then descended and approached Neville, offering a package. Neville read the note while feeding the owl a handful of snacks. "Oh, it's a birthday present from Draco. That was nice of him; I don't really even know him very well."

The bird flapped its wings and launched itself into the air. It disappeared quickly into the sky, but not before crapping on Madame Longbottom.

"That's enough of that", she announced. "I'm staying inside for a while."

She went inside and took a seat near a window where she could continue to watch everyone outside. As soon as she sat down, her hat vulture struggled and let out a cry. It then crapped, the liquid splattering the side of her face and the front of her robes. Everyone began laughing, some choking, and others laughing at those who were choking.

"Harry", Neville asked, after he'd located Harry and caught his breath, "I think this has somehow been both my best and worst birthday party ever. Did you snap your fingers or what?"

"I understand completely. And I can neither confirm nor deny whether I got you back-"

Hermione interrupted, "Harry, knock that off. What did you do?"

Harry just smirked, reaching into his pouch and tossing her an empty can of comed-tea. "It's a definite possibility that the drinks at this party have been spiked."

But Harry found himself confused. It strained credulity that all of this was already coincidentally going to happen in one time and place, such that someone could be compelled to give everyone present a comed-tea. But that left him with the original, even less probable, idea, that comed-tea altered the universe to produce comedy set-ups. There had to be something else going on here. And perhaps more strangely, comed-tea mixed with butter-beer apparently produced humor of a much more slapstick variety than pure comed-tea. For the latter, Harry decided, he could at least tell himself that the comedy adapts to its audience, but the former was going to bother him until he understood it. Maybe Fred and George had staged the whole thing and only asked him to snap to create plausible deniability... Harry smiled; the more creatively those two learned to think, the more formidable they would become.

Harry and Hermione were on the roof of Harry's office. It wasn't as comfortable as his office for getting work done, but it was far more inspiring, especially at night.

"Hermione, would you mind reading over this for me?"

"Sure, Harry, what is it?"

"I'm writing a speech for Bones to give to the Wizengamot to convince them to decommission Azkaban. I've gone through the most inspiring and persuasive speeches in muggle history, and tried to replicate what makes them effective. I'm not very optimistic, but I'm running out of things to try."

Hermione took the parchment and read for a moment, while Harry laid on his back watching the stars, "It reads like a speech. I can't think of how to improve it. But I doubt it will change anything either. Some social changes just require a new generation in power before they can happen."

"Twenty to forty more years of those abominations destroying the life and magic of human beings? There must be a better solution than that. Peter Pettigrew has been out of the prison for over a month. I've been told he's been healing but still hasn't spoken, and his magic should be slowly returning, but he hasn't cast anything, even accidentally. There are probably others who are also innocent, and there are certainly people who were cruelly sentenced over accidents, all overlooked by a system that cares more about inspiring fear and obedience than administering justice. You should read about the Stanford Prison Experiment. It basically showed that, under certain conditions, most people can be turned into monsters. I suspect-"

"I have read about it, actually. Including lots of criticism of the methods and conclusions, from bias in selecting participants, to relying entirely on subjective observations, and a total lack of control groups or blinding. The simplest explanation seems to be that Phillip Zimbardo was a sociopath and a handful of the participants were strongly influenced by conformity effects to behave as they believed he wanted."

There was a brief pause as Harry considered this.

"You could always order them to close the prison and destroy the dementors yourself if they refuse", Hermione suggested.

Harry smiled sadly, "You have no idea how many times I've thought about doing exactly that. I really should have done it the first time I had the chance... Anyway, killing a dementor is not without risk. Killing all of them... I can't risk dying to end one problem in one small corner of the world when I'm responsible for saving all of civilization and possibly all life."

"You could teach other people how to kill dementors, and go in with a small army. Then everyone would face a lower risk."

"That's currently plan A, but finding people who are trustworthy takes time, determining that they're capable of learning the necessary spell takes time, and waiting for them to learn occlumency takes time. It will take years to prepare that army."

"You said you'd teach me after I learned occlumency. How long do you think it will be until I've learned it well enough?"

"Actually, uh, I think you've stopped getting better at occlumency. Not everyone has a personality type that can become a successful occlumens. But I've been thinking this over: you can put up an almost-complete block, which is enough to stop most legilimens, the Wizengamot can't legally force one of its own members to take veritaserum, and Mad-eye can hunt down and obliviate anyone who gets the secret. It's a risk, but I think it's worth it. This part should be easier for you than learning occlumency; first you have to solve a riddle."

Hermione stared at him incredulously, "Riddle? I have to solve a riddle to kill dementors? Where are you getting your 'mysterious old wizard' instructions?" She paused, then looked slightly scared, "Dumbledore didn't write a manual for you, did he?"

"You'll understand when you understand. I'm looking for an abstract concept: what do people fear, but not animals? What is impossible to kill? What is so horrible that the mind refuses to process it?"

"I want to say 'trolls', but that isn't a concept. At least not 'troll' the animal; 'troll' the grade fits... But I'm guessing 'death' is the answer you're looking for."

Harry nodded, frowning. "My next question was going to be 'what dark creature best fits that concept' but you already got that answer wrong."

"Well, Professor Quirrell called dementors the second most perfect killing machine, and that's obviously what we're talking about. Oh, this makes sense: that's why people see them as waterlogged corpses. And I suppose it makes sense, as far as magic ever does, that distracting yourself with happy thoughts calls up a magic animal which is immune to the fear of death."

Harry nodded again, smiling this time. "Not everyone who can't produce a patronus is unhappy; many of them are the kind of person who can't use a happy distraction to escape an unpleasant truth."

"And you haven't told people this because the knowledge might prevent them from using a patronus at all." It wasn't a question. "So what's the solution; you can produce a patronus anyway, right?"

"The answer is obvious: you don't try to distract yourself. You stare death in the metaphorical face, comprehend it, fill your mind with happy thoughts, then cast a patronus using the thought of conquering death, of a future where death is just a bad memory. My first time I was staring into a literal dementor, but I suspect that you can imagine staring death in the face easily enough without one. Anyway, I ran through every happy thought I could, then finished with picturing the earth among the stars, and the future of human civilization, having inherited the galaxy and having advanced far beyond anything so mundane as a dementor. Expecto patronum!" A flash from his wand formed into a silvery humanoid.

Harry continued, "That produces a better type of patronus: it can blind, disable, or even permanently destroy dementors. It lets you put a lot more into it", the patronus brightened until it was painful to look at, "but that's also dangerous because it's powered by one's life as well as magic." Harry let the patronus fade away.

A moment later there was a new silvery humanoid on the roof. Hermione sat down, hard, next to Harry.

"So that's the secret to destroying dementors. And you said it's powered by life. So someone could die by putting too much life into this?"

"It's a definite risk. If it were safe and easy, I'd hunt dementors as a hobby."

They were both silent for a few minutes, watching the stars. Harry saw the light moving in the sky, and checked his watch, smiling. Hermione noticed it a moment later. "Harry, what is that? It looks like it's headed here." Harry nodded and climbed to his feet, Hermione stood as well.

The phoenix slowed to a hover in front of them and cawed loudly at Hermione. She turned to Harry, "So I'm the one who has to be the hero. I'm going to go, Harry."

He nodded again, "I know; it wouldn't be you if you could make any other choice." Hermione touched the phoenix's talon and they disappeared in a fiery flash.

Harry let himself show a mischievous smile and reached for his time-turner. He mentally checked off the 'obtain a phoenix for Hermione' part of his master plan, and moved on to the next item: he intended to test the hypothesis that phoenices came from the mirror. But before he could activate the time-turner, he was interrupted by the flash of the phoenix returning. Alone. The phoenix called out, looking around, appearing confused. "What the hell did you do?" Harry demanded.

Chief Warlock (as far as everyone knew) Bones didn't even try to hide her exasperated sigh from the assembled Wizengamot. She had naively hoped the absence of the usual evil faction would allow the rest of the assembly to get useful things done. Unfortunately, even though they weren't murderous bigots, they were still politicians.

To make matters worse, that kid, despite clearly believing in this cause, had ordered her to sabotage it if necessary "for now". He had made the dubious claim that her efforts either way wouldn't matter in the end and this way she could possibly gain the trust of the new Wizengamot dark faction. Then he had ominously added 'also, other reasons', which especially does not inspire confidence when said by a dark-wizard generated possible ticking-time-bomb.

"Why should we prepare to transfer anyone to a different prison? We have a perfectly good one already", asked some nameless businessman.

Tiberius Ogden responded, beginning to lose his temper, "I told you why: one, dementors are a disgusting punishment, fit for only the worst of the worst offenders and everyone knows it. And that's not just bleeding-heart sentiment; there are real-world consequences. It hurts our international credibility: other countries don't trust our motives when we try to build international coalitions against threats. They were even willing to ignore Voldemort at his worst. Two, we have a higher crime rate than most countries because petty criminals (such as unregistered animagi or ward-breakers-for-hire) are allowed to operate with impunity; sending them to Azkaban would be unjust so such sentences are rarely applied. And that's not even addressing the issue of falsely imprisoned innocents, such as Mr. Pettigrew. Three, dementors do not make a secure prison. They're not trustworthy without a relatively large group of specially trained aurors. And they prevent most other defenses from being employed effectively. Bellatrix Black escaped and is still at large. No one has escaped Nurmengard."

"As Director of Magical Law Enforcement, you told us that you fixed the security problems. Is that accurate?" Umbridge addressed Bones with a smile.

"As you already know", Bones began with a glare, "the addition of new wards and precautions should prevent that method from working again. All prisoners are now checked for animagus forms when they enter the prison and the time visitors can spend there with patroni is strictly limited. The anti-flight wards were upgraded to cover all unauthorized magical flight, and a device was added that casts 'arresto momento' on all unauthorized objects or individuals a few times per second. Mr. Weasley at Misuse of Muggle Artifacts has thus far been unable to procure a suitable device for testing those wards, but we believe they will be sufficient." After Dumbledore's disappearance, she had personally added a ward to prevent phoenices from teleporting into the prison while allowing the individuals transported by the phoenix a one-way trip, but she had decided that no one needed to know about that.

"But the prison is still largely dependent on dementors", Ogden replied. "A modern magical prison, with solid walls and doors, locked with colloportus, and covered with various shielding charms and tampering alarms would be far better."

"And how much would renting space in a foreign prison and transferring all those people cost? Or worse, constructing a new prison?" asked Lady Greengrass, playing the role of someone competent and prudent.

Umbridge interrupted, "That's a great question, but I know what we could do to improve security for free: order the dementors to keep at least one of their number in the prison at all times, with orders to kiss anyone caught outside of the cells. Visitors must be escorted by aurors at all times. We can charge the visitors for the cost of any additional aurors required."

Bones fought down the familiar urge to punch Umbridge in the face or try futilely to teach the idiots about single point failures or always fighting the last war, took a deep breath, tapped the Line of Merlin against the podium, and called for a vote.

Note: Skepticism has been expressed for Amelia Bones' ability to create a phoenix ward so quickly, given that phoenices are so powerful. I don't believe this is an issue because 1) HPMOR doesn't operate on a power hierarchy, it operates on the principle that 'even the greatest artifact can be defeated by a counter-artifact that is lesser, but specialized' 2) Amelia Bones is one of the smartest and most knowledgeable characters in the story, and 3) she was annoyed by Dumbledore's ability to show up wherever he felt like, so she was likely investigating phoenix warding on and off for the past decade even if she decided against implementing it until after he disappeared.

Chapter 5: Azkaban 2.0

Here's how it is:

During the summer after the events of HPMOR, Harry remains deeply concerned about the fate of the world, despite Hermione obtaining a phoenix and destroying Azkaban's dementors, Moody having made progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital, and Bones apparently grudgingly willing to take his cues on national policy.

Moody is suspicious of Gilderoy Lockhart, McGonagall's new hire for Defense professor. But that's nothing new, and Moody has found no evidence of wrongdoing in spite of putting some effort into investigating him. Moody, Bones, McGonagall, and Hermione are all concerned about Harry's apparent desire to release Voldemort from the ring in order to question him about the mirror and help rescue Dumbledore. Sprout has mysteriously received a gift: the long-lost and apparently cursed Hufflepuff Cup.

Draco is angry at the world; at the perceived failures and betrayals of everyone around him. In a flash of incite, Draco concludes that Harry is Voldemort and is the biggest threat to magical society. He begins planning to amass power for the inevitable battle.

Harry nodded, a slight shiver going through him. "Um, when you told me about what happened in Godric's Hollow, on Halloween night, in 1981 I mean, um... I thought I saw another flaw in your reasoning. A way you could have avoided disaster. But, um, I think you have a blind spot, a class of strategies you don't consider, so you didn't see it even afterward-"

Harry swallowed a lump in his throat. "There wass way for you to tesst your horcrux ssysstem without dying. The general lesson is important. Do you see it now?"

"No," Professor Quirrell said after a while. "And I do hope your lesson is a sensible one, for your sake."

"Suppose, Professor, that I learned how to cast the improved horcrux spell and I was willing to use it. What would I do with it?"

Professor Quirrell answered at once. "You would find some person whom you found morally abhorrent and whose death you could convince yourself would save other lives, and murder them to create a horcrux."

"And then what?"

"Make more horcruxes," said the Defense Professor. He picked up a jar of what looked like dragon scales.

"Before that," Harry said.

After a time the Defense Professor shook his head. "I still do not see it, and you will cease this game and tell me."

"I would make horcruxes for my friends. If you'd ever really cared about one single other person in the entire world, if there'd been just one person who gave your immortality meaning, someone that you wanted to live forever with you -" Harry's throat choked. "Then, then the idea of making a horcrux for someone else wouldn't have been such a counterintuitive thought." Harry was blinking hard. "You have a blind spot around strategies that involve doing nice things for other people, to the point where it stops you from achieving your selfish values. You think... it's not your style, I suppose. That... particular part of your self-image... is what cost you those nine years."

"I see..." the Defense Professor said slowly. "I see. I should have taught Rabastan the advanced horcrux ritual, and forced him to test the invention. Yes, that is supremely obvious in retrospect. For that matter, I could have ordered Rabastan to try marking himself onto some disposable infant, to see what happened, before I took myself to Godric's Hollow to create you." Professor Quirrell shook his head bemusedly. "Well. I am glad I am realizing this now and not ten years earlier; I had enough to chide myself for at that time."

"You don't see nice ways to do the things you want to do," Harry said. His ears heard a note of desperation in his own voice. "Even when a nice strategy would be more effective you don't see it because you have a self-image of not being nice."

"That is a fair observation," said Professor Quirrell. "Indeed, now that you have pointed it out, I have just now thought of some nice things I can do this very day, to further my agenda."

Harry just looked at him.

Professor Quirrell was smiling. "Your lesson is a good one, Mr. Potter. From now on, until I learn the trick of it, I shall keep diligent watch for cunning strategies that involve doing kindnesses for other people. Go and practice acts of goodwill, perhaps, until my mind goes there easily."

Cold chills ran down Harry's spine.

Professor Quirrell had said this without the slightest visible hesitation.

Lord Voldemort was absolutely certain that he could never be redeemed. He wasn't the tiniest bit afraid of it happening to him.

Harry awoke with a groan and checked the time. Four o'clock in the morning. Harry pushed himself to his feet, groaning again. At least he'd be able to get some work done before Moody arrived and prevented him from doing anything useful for the rest of the day...

The silence in Harry's office was interrupted by a pop as a short, long-eared creature appeared. "What the hell?"

"Hogwarts is being too dangerous, Harry Potter must leave Hog-"

The creature teleported away just in time to avoid the burst of stunners aimed at and around it.

Harry cursed as she metamorphosed into Auror Tonks, while Harry pulled back the hood of his invisibility cloak.

Harry shook his head, "That was new. I was expecting something to take advantage of the interruption in the wards, but certainly I wasn't expecting that."

Tonks smirked, "I thought being a body-double slash body-guard for a twelve-year-old was silly before, but now that I know Moody sent me to protect you from rogue house elves... Yeah, that's probably the weirdest thing I've seen this week. It's been a slow week."

"It's been a pretty full week for me, though that's probably in my top ten. It could have been much worse; Moody was probably expecting some new incarnation of Voldemort to appear and that you'd have to sacrifice yourself to fake my death or at least stall the attack long enough for him to bring reinforcements."

Tonks frowned, "That... is probably closer to the truth than you think it is."

"I'm still surprised he, and the headmistress, agreed to allow the warding specialists to interrupt some of the wards to study how they interact."

"Yeah, and it's really too bad the creature detection ward is down. It would have been nice to know where that elf came from or ran away to. People always make investigations harder than they ought to be."

Bones stepped through the floo and glared at Hermione, specifically, at her phoenix. "Of course you two were responsible for Azkaban. I never doubted it for a moment, but there's the smoking responsible adults cleaned up your mess without incident this time."

Harry turned to Hermione, "Yeah, you probably need to keep the phoenix hidden from teachers, students, etc. for a while. Like until the next time you do something heroic and dangerous."

"I guess even Fawkes wouldn't go along with a prison break", Moody added. "How did you get another phoenix, anyway?"

Harry answered, "The normal way; when someone plans on doing something heroic and crazy and dangerous, one shows up somehow. I'm still investigating the details. Also, since when has Azkaban blocked phoenix travel? I remember Fawkes took Dumbledore there."

"Well, if someone had told me about what you were planning, I probably would have explained the new wards. It's not like I can predict what crazy things you're going to do."

Harry shrugged, "Fair enough-"

Hermione interrupted, "Fawkes probably would have helped. We could have waited and come up with an actual plan and found out about the anti-phoenix wards and the tripping jinxes and everything else.I didn't think about it at the time, but it really wasn't urgent that I left at that second."

Bones added, "Or if we'd seriously tried, we may have been able to convince the Wizengamot to close the prisonwithout the vigilantism."

Harry closed his eyes, "It was urgent. You only get one chance to accept a phoenix."

Hermione scowled, "I thought you guys tried to get the Wizengamot to close the prison. And basically concluded it wasn't going to happen."

"Actually, I just had Bones say that so you'd be in the right state of mind to attract a phoenix."

"Harry, you lied to me!"

"I think it's very, very important that you have a phoenix. The safest way to get one is to plan a mission one believes is urgent and dangerous but really isn't."

"You should have asked first; you promised."

"That wouldn't have worked. For a phoenix to show up, you need to believe you're doing the right thing, that it's going to be dangerous even with help from a phoenix, and again, you only get one chance. And I wish someone had manipulated me into getting a phoenix. Although if I'd known your phoenix would be defective, I might not have bothered with it."

"As glad as I am to have Hermes, you have to stop manipulating people like this."

"I've been meaning to ask about that name; the messenger of the gods. Does that mean you've found a new ambition?"

"Don't change the subject, Harry-"

McGonagall interrupted, "Actually, if you can postpone this fight until later, I assume there are more important topics on the agenda?"

Bones nodded, "Bellatrix was at Gringotts. The goblins have been spectacularly unhelpful but we've been able to determine that she flooed in a few weeks ago, accessed her vault, and left without incident. The floo system reported unexpected activity at the Black family home to the DMLE, but it looked like she had moved on at least a week earlier and there are no further leads and no usable witness reports."

Hermione frowned, "No one saw her at Gringotts? She was there during normal business hours, right?"

Bones scowled, "We've tracked down a few people who apparently saw her. You'd think people would recognize the most wanted woman in magical Britain, but apparently not if she dyes her hair blond."

Harry asked, "Not even with a missing arm?"

"According to the witnesses, her limbs were intact and there was nothing suspicious about her. Basically no one knows anything useful. The bottom line is you should stay inside the wards here until she's apprehended."

"Speaking of the which, did the ward specialists learn everything they needed to know to set something up at Hogwarts?"

Moody chuckled, "The only thing they learned was how much they don't know. They said they'll need to investigate for at least a year to be able to make even simple modifications."

Harry scowled, "That's totally unacceptable. How about this as a temporary alternative: We build the arrival and departure rooms outside the wards as planned, with hallways that lead underground. But instead of building an underground hospital, we just leave it as two rooms, from which Hermes teleports people to random rooms in Azkaban. Fawkes holds the Philosopher's Stone and takes it to the rooms where it's needed. We recruit someone in each of the world's major magical hospitals to report their terminal patients, after which someone stuns, time-turns, and then teleports them to the arrival room. After treatment, they're taken to wait in the departure room and returned to the hospital the instant they left."

Moody nodded, "The basics sound workable; Azkaban does have pretty solid warding to start with. I'll work out the details for the hospital liaisons, which will take a little time, but I should be able to get St. Mungo's on board within the week. International hospitals may present some issues."

"Other governments have three general options: to cooperate, to stall, or to actively try to attack or sabotage the hospital. We need a situation where cooperation is the Nash equilibrium choice for each government. Countries shouldn't interfere if the likely outcome of that interference (including reactions by other countries) is worse than the status quo. I'll have to think more about it, but I'd guess that threatening to withhold treatment from leaders of countries that do annoying things would probably be sufficient."

Bones smirked, "You make it sound like politics should be an arithmancy exercise. Let me know how that works out for you."

"I know there are more details to work out there, and your advice would be appreciated. Take some time to think it over and we'll talk about it later."

Bones nodded unenthusiastically.

"Is there any news about Peter?", McGonagall asked.

Bones sighed. "At the moment, no one knows where he is. As you know, Peter Pettigrew was taken from Azkaban to St. Mungo's weeks ago. Physically, he was reportedly recovering, psychologically, not so much. He hadn't spoken or demonstrated any magical ability, including metamorphosing back to his original form. Then he disappeared from the hospital."

"Oh...", Harry began. "Wait, never mind..."

"So he was Sirius after all then", Moody concluded.

Bones replied, "Well, the investigators can't be sure it was really Sirius who was killed by Voldemort. They don't know anything. That's not in report i mean, of course."

"I can certainly understand someone who was imprisoned for a decade without a trial fleeing magical Britain at their earliest opportunity," McGonagall argued.

Harry concluded, "There are four general possibilities, between which I can't distinguish with the current evidence: One, Sirius became a death eater, betrayed my parents, then got Peter imprisoned in his place. Two, Sirius was a death eater, but ended up in Azkaban while metamorphosed Peter was killed by Voldemort that night. Three, Peter was the traitor but was smart and/or cowardly enough to use Sirius' form to do illegal things, eventually getting Sirius arrested in his place. And four, Peter used Sirius' appearance as a death eater, but Sirius then got Peter justly arrested. So basically, I think we know less now than we thought we knew a few weeks ago."

"I don't think that changes anything", Bones replied. "Aurors will continue to search for him, and we'll get it settled after they apprehend him."

"He could be a security threat, but with reduced magic and likely limited mental function, he's unlikely to be more dangerous than anyone else", Moody added. "Speaking of suspicious and probably dangerous people, what are you planning to do about Lockhart?"

McGonagall answered dryly, "pay him to teach defense."

"That's a mistake. That man is either into something so dark I don't know how to detect it or he's just been lucky. Either way, he's a bad choice for a defense teacher."

Harry interjected, "I'm surprised you believe in luck, actually."

Moody's human eye stared at Harry, "It'll be in your 6th or 7th year potions text. Only a few wizards have ever been able to brew it, so I assume he bought, inherited, or stole some."

Harry lowered his face into his hands. "A potion that makes luck? You've got to be kidding me. With instructions that everyone knows about but almost no one can use? Why does that sound familiar? It's got to be another cover story for some secret artifact. I guess that's another entry for the list of artifacts we need to collect." Harry looked around the room, "So is there anything else we need to talk about?"

Bones shrugged, "It's probably nothing but you get weird about these things. Some aurors reported a glowing person rising through the core of Azkaban after the dementors disappeared. One of the muggleborns referred to it as an angel and a handful of people are convinced it's part of some muggle end-of-the-world prophecy and are taking the whole thing far more seriously than I'd consider healthy."

"A messenger of a different god", Harry smirked. "Hermione, I'm definitely noticing a pattern..."

Hermione walked down a random hallway. She was trying to decide for how long she should refuse to speak to Harry, or if there were a more effective behavior modification method, when Professor Sprout walked through an intersection and paused to talk.

"Hermione, I'm sorry I haven't been available much this summer. I don't know how I got this busy. I heard you passed a fair number of OWLs anyway, so congratulations; that's very impressive. Anyway, one of the projects I've been working on involves some really interesting charms research that I could use some help with, if you're interested..."

Chapter 11: Winning and Losing

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world, but has made significant progress: Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors, and Acting Chief Warlock Bones is grudgingly taking his cues on national policy. Progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities and a temporary solution has been set up in the now-abandoned Azkaban tower.

Sprout received a mysterious gift, the long-lost and apparently cursed Hufflepuff Cup, and displayed uncharacteristically aggressive behavior afterwards. Moody detected evidence of dark magic on her but it was inconclusive. Since then, Moody has researched more specific spells for detecting horcrux effects and, as one might expect, Hermione tested positive. Draco, after finding the Riddle Diary, showed some very dark-wizard-like thoughts and behaviors such as working to amass power and followers for himself, and brutally knocking down anyone who gets in his way.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. Bellatrix is still at large and able to appear in public despite topping Magical Britain's most wanted list.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and helping Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped.

"You ssaid no time," came the snake's hiss, "but plan iss for you to rule country, obvioussly, even your young noble friend hass undersstood that by now, assk him on return if you wissh...

"Learn all that I have to teach you, Mr. Potter, and you will rule this country in time. Then you may tear down the prison that democracy made, if you find that Azkaban still offends your sensibilities. Like it or not, Mr. Potter, you have seen this day that your own will conflicts with the will of this country's populace, and that you do not bow your head and submit to their decision when that occurs. So to them, whether or not they know it, and whether or not you acknowledge it, you are their next Dark Lord...

"To free yoursself, to gain power in Britain, you musst again be sseen to defeat the Dark Lord. You are kidnapped from Hogwartss to public location, many witnesssess, wardss keep out protectorss. Dark Lord announcess that he hass at long lasst regained physical form, after wandering as sspirit for yearss; ssayss that he hass gained sstill greater power, not even you can sstop him now. Offerss to let you duel. You casst guardian Charm, Dark Lord laughss at you, ssayss he iss not life-eater. Casstss Killing Cursse at you, you block, watcherss ssee Dark Lord explode -"

"Casst Killing Cursse? " Harry hissed in incredulity. "At me? Again? Ssecond time? Nobody will believe Dark Lord could posssibly be that sstupid -"

The snake swayed thoughtfully. "Could write different sscript for play, if you wissh. Whatever sscenario, sshould leave open posssibility Dark Lord might return yet again - nation musst think they are sstill dependent on you to protect them."

"Too rissky," Harry said simply.

"If my plan iss not to your tasste, what iss yours?"

"If necesssary - sstay at sschool ssix yearss and sstudy. Hogwartss sseemss fine place to dwell. Bookss, friendss, sstrange but tassty food." Harry wanted to chuckle, but there wasn't any gesture in Parseltongue for the kind of laughter he wanted to express.

The pits of the snake's eyes seemed almost black. "Eassy to ssay that now. Ssuch as you and I, we do not tolerate imprissonment. You will losse patience long before sseventh year, perhapss before end of thiss one. I sshall plan accordingly."

Harry slowly opened his eyes, then closed and rubbed them. He sighed. Voldemort's claimed goal for him bore an uncanny resemblance to the current reality: he had apparently defeated Voldemort, though he'd given Hermione public credit. He had a seat on the Wizengamot (and was secretly its Chief Warlock). He had access to a surprising amount of powerful magic (including the Philosopher's Stone, the Mirror, two Deathly Hallows, two phoenices, and Hogwarts itself). Harry decided to raise his probability estimate for the hypothesis that Voldemort was still... active, which also raised the probability estimate that he was responsible for the events at Hogwarts.

Voldemort had once promised (in Parseltongue) not to harm him, so long as he didn't attack Voldemort. Even though Voldemort had apparently planned for Harry to attack him and then kill Harry (or have death eaters kill him) all along. Had that deception been carefully worded enough to be permitted by Parseltongue, or was it evidence Voldemort had found a more general way to lie in Parseltongue?

Even if Voldemort had heard a prophecy implying Harry would do something apocalyptic, prophecies weren't known for providing useful specifics, like names and dates. Therefore Voldemort would've had to consider every possible interpretation, including the possibility that either the subject of the prophecy was someone else or the meaning was something else. And Voldemort had already guessed that Dumbledore had a source of information about the future, so it should have raised a red flag that Dumbledore (who'd let his own brother die rather than negotiate with Voldemort) would sacrifice himself for Harry (and not even to guarantee Harry's safety, but to give Harry a chance as a hostage of a mass murderer rather than a certainty of being locked outside time). Strangely, Voldemort had not only been unsurprised, his plan had depended on Dumbledore's decision. In retrospect, it couldn't have been more obvious that Dumbledore considered Harry the most important person in the world. And Voldemort had predicted that somehow. Had Voldemort determined details of the prophecies Dumbledore had heard by observing his prior behavior?

Harry's eyes widened as he bolted upright. Temporary memory charms existed; Dumbledore had used them to hide Narcissa. Voldemort had used a confundus charm to beat the ancient mirror. Obliviation would beat veritaserum. Was that all it took to lie in Parseltongue?

Harry let out a brief laugh despite himself; it would be even more interesting if memory charms didn't fool Parseltongue because searching for differences between what one believed and what one could hiss out loud would provide a way to detect memory charms. Harry decided he needed to test this at his earliest convenience.

Harry rolled out of bed, deciding to put off homework until after breakfast. He wanted to spend a few hours practicing analytic charms and working on spells for some charmed objects he'd need later in the week. Because if Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres entered a competition, he meant to win.

An artifact that just turns off lights? Why would Dumbledore make this? He could already dispel any magical light, extinguish any fire, cool anything incandescent, and interrupt any electrical circuit using basic charms. For him, such things wouldn't normally require anything close to his full power level. The object's existence was senseless.

At least Harry's vow was no longer pushing for its immediate destruction, as he was sufficiently convinced that directing it at the sun wouldn't disrupt solar fusion.

Knowing Dumbledore, it was probably a necessary component of some Rube Goldbergesque plan, without which all life would be doomed. Harry sighed, resting his forehead on his palm, and dropped the object into his pouch.

Harry cleared his desk, re-shelving a few books and leaning a long wooden rod against the wall. He pulled a hooded cloak from his pouch, spread it out on the desk, leveled his wand at it and began to concentrate.

"What in Merlin's name did I ever do to you people?", Neville asked exasperatedly. Facing three upperclassmen alone was the scariest thing he'd experienced in a while, but he was trying his hardest not to show it; Harry would never show fear.

Derrick smirked, "Your choice of friends offends me. Also H-"

Neville had been practicing dueling all summer, but he wasn't anywhere near this good. Luckily he'd planned ahead. "Earmuffs", he instructed his pouch. "Sorry, guys, Listening to idiots is bad for my health, so..." He quickly backed up and ducked around a corner, avoiding several spells which impacted the opposite wall.

After pulling on the earmuffs, all he could hear was the sound of blood rushing through his own ears. He clearly wasn't missing anything because the Slytherin, who had now turned the corner and faced Neville, was yelling enough to turn his face red.

Neville was brushing a finger against the pouch; Harry had taught him that he could retrieve objects by spelling rather than saying them. He lifted the pot with one hand, while uprooting the mandrake inside with the other. The other students instantly fell over, stunned.

Neville hit each one with a stupify, just to be safe, before carefully replanting the mandrake and returning it to his pouch. He then collected their wands and applied sticking charms between their hands and the ground. "That should hold them for long enough."

As Neville walked away, Draco stepped out from behind another corner, muttering to himself, "And I thought it would be suspicious for two second years to defeat more than three upperclassmen at once. I have to stop overestimating my minions. And think of some better plans. Enervate."

As they woke up, he continued, "Well, that was a waste. How am I supposed to rescue Neville from you people if he can handle you on his own? But because I am a reasonable lord, I will release you from the trap you got yourselves stuck in. This time. Finite incantatem." He walked away.

"Um, what happened?"

"Where are our wands?"

Neville walked toward the Great Hall, passing the Weasley twins along the way.

"Hey, Fred, George. Do you guys have any fast-acting glue?"

Fred narrowed his eyes, "Yeah, what do you need it for?"

"Trust me, if this works, you'll want to see it."

George shrugged, "Well, I'm curious."

"Me, too", Fred agreed.

Neville pulled out the three wands and set them on the floor. He held the first wand by its handle in his left hand and applied a liberal coat of glue to about a third of the opposite end. He used his own wand to cast a hover charm at it and propelled the wand to the ceiling. After holding it for thirty seconds Neville canceled the hover charm, "finite incantatem... Cool, that actually worked."

"Why did you only put glue on the front of the wand and not the handle?"

"Well, snapping a wand is one of those things you just never do to someone. But if they're stupid enough to snap their own wands by yanking on them hard enough, that's not technically my fault."

Fred and George stared at the ceiling for a second, blinked, then simultaneously exclaimed, "My turn!", grabbing one of the remaining wands. A minute later, all three wands were solidly glued to the high ceiling of the Great Hall.

"Neville, that was brilliant!"

"We really need to step up our game."

"It's too bad Filch isn't still around. He always deserved anything we came up with."

"Maybe we should check up on his replacement?"

"Uh, Neville, whose wands were those anyway?"

Blaise set up a poster containing a large grid and yelled out, "Bets! Place your bets here!"

Members of the Gryffindor quidditch team arrived at the front of the crowd, betting on Ron by between one and three seconds.

The Hufflepuff team evened things up a bit, betting anywhere between Harry by two seconds and Ron by two seconds, except for Cedric who bet on Harry by two to three seconds.

Gregory bet Harry by three to four seconds, which Vincent matched. Theodore followed them, betting on Harry by four to five seconds.

Gregory frowned, "Ron's flying a Nimbus 2000. No matter how well someone can fly, I can't see them beating a Nimbus by more than maybe three and a half seconds on a flight this long. Do you know something I don't or are you just hoping to win the pot if Ron falls into the lake or something?"

Lavender added, "Yeah, I know Harry's good at flying, but he can't be that much better than Ron."

Theodore shrugged, "I don't know anything you don't. But it is General Chaos."

Padma added, "Yeah, Harry will always do something unexpected."

Gregory appeared offended as Seamus bet next, on Harry to win by five to six seconds, and Tracey bet on Harry by six to seven. "What are you people thinking? You know how brooms work and-"

Lavender interrupted, "Wait, if you expect him to do something unexpected, then is it-"

Dean interrupted, "At least you're all allowed to bet. Stupid conflict of interest. That's what I get for agreeing to help."

Percy and Penelope walked over and inspected Blaise's betting board.

Penelope frowned at Blaise, "There are rules against betting on Hogwarts sporting events."

Blaise smiled broadly, "While this competition may or may not meet the definition of a 'sport' (which by the way, is not clearly defined in the Hogwarts handbook or supporting documents), it was neither organized nor sanctioned by the school and is therefore not a Hogwarts sporting event."

"A technicality-"

"Not at all, the rules ban gambling only in certain specific circumstances, such as Hogwarts official sporting events, or when and how Defense professors will turn evil. That implies that gambling in any other context is acceptable. Also, I'm donating 10% of all bets to a charity. You wouldn't want to deprive those war orphans of food would you? I can tell you wouldn't do that; you're definitely not a monster."

Then Percy asked, "Your options only go up to the 'nine to ten second' box. What happens if no one wins? You keep all the money?"

Blaise frowned, "It's impossible for anyone to win by more than ten seconds no matter how badly they screw up. I suppose the giant squid could grab one of them or something, but I'm sure in that case, they'd re-run the race."

Percy replied, "Then you should say you'll refund all the bets if someone wins by more than ten seconds. Or, if you change those boxes to say 'nine or more seconds', I'll put a galleon on Harry."

Blaise and Penelope looked at Percy, surprised. Blaise replied, "Oh, sorry, I didn't realize this was a business negotiation. I'd be happy to let you place that bet." He inked a quill and quickly amended the 'nine to ten seconds' heading to 'more than nine seconds' and Percy handed him a galleon.

Penelope looked at Percy questioningly. He shrugged, "He's right; it's not actually against the rules. And how often do you find a sure thing?"

Fred and George glanced at each other, then handed Blaise more coins, gesturing at the 'more than nine seconds' box.

Tracey, Seamus, Nott didn't have more money on them, but attempted to change their bets.

"No refunds or transfers", Blaise announced. "Also, betting is now closed; it looks like the race is starting."

Dean attempted to yell over the multiple conversations until Harry cast a sonorus charm on him. Dean's voice then carried easily, "Okay, today we're going to have a broomstick race out and back over the lake. I'm Dean Thomas and I'll be the judge and announcer for this event. Ginny Weasley and Colin Creevey are line judges at the far side of the lake; one of them will throw red sparks when Ron reaches the edge of the lake, and the other will throw blue sparks when Harry gets there. Oh, right... Your contestants for today are Ronald Weasley of Gryffindor on a brand new Nimbus 2000, and Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres of Ravenclaw on a... something that looks more like a coat rack with a bowl stuck to it than a broom?"

Harry lifted the broom and pointed. Dean reads out, "It's apparently a model 'UR2L8'... oh, I get it... Anyway..." Dean lifted into the air on his broom and called, "Contestants to their starting positions!"

Ron called 'up' and quickly darted to where Dean indicated the starting line.

Harry held out his broom and tapped it with his wand. He then climbed onto it, rotated the parabolic pusher plate to point down and quietly cast 'ventus' against it. He slowly rose into the air after them and, after some maneuvering, took his place at the starting line, though he wasn't quite pointed in the correct direction.

Ron pointed and laughed, "Beating you on that... piece of trash won't even be fun. I thought you delayed this race so you could get a real racing broom."

Harry shrugged, "It's a magically propelled vehicle. If you'd like to challenge whether it meets the rules, please do that now, before the race."

Ron just scoffed.

As Dean called the start of the race, they both shot out over the lake. For the first few seconds, they were dead even, though Harry's broom fish-tailed disconcertingly. Then Ron's Nimbus reached its maximum speed and Harry's broom pulled ahead, still accelerating.

A moment later, Harry saw the blue sparks around him and the broom instantly stopped. Then it accelerated backwards, spinning around and oscillating briefly before stabilizing. Harry rotated the pusher plate to the left and cast ventus against it, giving him a larger margin of safety from Ron's flight path as they quickly approached each other. Harry passed the finish line and immediately stopped. He then turned the parabola upward and cast ventus into it, causing the broom to slowly descend.

A moment later, Ron landed, yelling, "You cheated!"

Harry sighed, "I told you that's what you would say; that's why I made you write out the rules. And I haven't broken even one of them."

"So what was the official time?", Tracey called to Dean.

"Uh, technically, the race isn't over yet. No red sparks means Ron never actually made it to the far side of the lake." He turned to Ron, "Right now, you're thirty seconds behind. Are you planning to finish, or do you just want to give up now?"

Ron stormed off angrily.

Fred puts arm around Percy, "We need to get you to gamble more often", while George hold his hand out to Blaise, "You have our money yet?"

Percy pulled away from his brother and quietly addressed Harry, "So, we haven't covered brooms yet; what exactly is that?"

"Yeah, it's not exactly a normal broom. I used the hover charm from the target drones (which I assume brooms also use), added an 'arresto momento' to stop it, and other than that, there's just a spell that makes it accelerate north, and a spell that makes it accelerate south. I have to cast 'ventus' on it to do anything else."

What about turning?

"It doesn't. It just goes north and south as quickly as possible, which was optimal for the rules Ron wrote. It doesn't use spells to control its attitude either; these tail surfaces use aerodynamic forces to keep it pointed in the right direction once it's moving fast enough. Ron's rules only required it to be propelled magically, not for it to be stabilized magically."

Percy shook his head, "We'll have to discuss this again once we cover the broom chapter. It's suddenly more interesting to me than it was before."

"Yeah, I look forward to that."

Dean Thomas noticed Harry walking toward him and stopped, "Hey Harry, what's up?"

He then noticed Harry was carrying what looked likea torture device for candles: a wax cylinder with a long bolt running through its axis and into a motor and a needle sticking into the side of the cylinder. "And what's that?"

Harry smiled broadly, while holding the needle away from the wax and twisting the bolt. When finished, he gently placed the needle back onto the cylinder and started the motor, "... Harry, what's up ... nd ... ats ... that..."

"I can do sound recording and playback. It's not the greatest quality, but how well can you really expect wax to store analog audio data?"

"Cool. What does that mean?"

"The bottom line is, I don't know what will happen to a cassette player at Hogwarts, but it's definitely possible to play records here. So if you still want music, it's doable."

"That's great!"

"Also, I was wondering if you could help me with a related experiment."

"Uh, sure. What do you need?"

"On your trips home and back for Christmas break, take something electronic along and keep an eye on where it works and where it doesn't. I want to know as accurately as possible where the boundaries are. Electronics will work at your house, and not work at Hogwarts or the train platform. I'm not sure about the train itself or how close you can get to Hogwarts or the train station before things stop working."

"Oh. Okay, I can do that. Have you found anything else interesting?"

"I tried to make a telegraph. Everything worked, while it was in my office anyway. When I tried to connect a few different rooms together, everything inexplicably failed. It worked again when I dragged all the parts out into the hallway. I hypothesized that maybe circuits only work when the operator has a line of sight with all parts; most of the things that worked for me were basically laid out on breadboards, while my commercial watch and calculator are in plastic cases. But I quickly ruled that out because my AM transmitter didn't work, and that was on a breadboard. Then I thought about how radio waves travel through walls, and hypothesized that I may need a line of sight with all the effects of a circuit. But that still doesn't explain why ICs work despite being encased in plastic. I tried taking the circuit board out of the calculator, just in case that explanation was close to whatever is really going on, but that didn't help either. Next, I think I'll try to build a digital clock from components, then check individual sections of the circuit to see where it breaks down. But I think I'm going to take a break from circuits for a while. Some other projects I've been working on have been more rewarding recently."

Lockhart smiled brightly, "Welcome to the first meeting of the Hogwarts Dueling Club! We'll wait a few more minutes for stragglers to arrive, then get started."

Lavender smirked, "What is with that cloak? It looks ridiculous. Is that even a real color? I didn't know blue could look like that."

Harry nodded, "Yup. I'm aware of this."

Parvati added, "And you wore it on purpose? And what's with the triangles? Wait, they're not triangles, they're pyramid shaped dents. That's got to be uncomfortable."

Harry shrugged, "The biggest problem is that it's too hot. I have to keep casting cooling charms on it."

Ron smirked, "It's still not as bright as Lockhart's robe. Maybe this is Harry's way of sucking up to the Defense professor this year."

Harry shrugged again.

"Where's Hermione?", Susan asked.

"She's not coming. I don't really blame her after her last experience with dueling", Padma opined.

Harry forced himself to nod along, despite strongly suspecting that Hermione would have loved a chance to show off; it was just too soon for her abilities to become publicly known and she wasn't that good at acting.

Lockhart clapped once and announced, "Okay, let's get started. For now, we'll just get a feel for where everyone is. First to disarm or stun your opponent wins, and don't use anything dangerous or you'll be banned from the club. All of you, line up along that wall. You and you, and all of you, line up there. Spread out evenly and face your first opponent. Let's start out at a distance of about 10 meters. That should be close enough to be a targeting challenge for some of you, but close enough that you'll have to dodge from the first shot."

Harry looked across the room and saw Ginny. He muttered, "Come on, is this a joke? Fighting a firstie? Give me a real opponent."

Lockhart was walking nearby and overheard, "We'll rotate in a moment. But don't underestimate. Rule #5: it's better to be lucky than good." Lockhart laughed as if someone had told an hilarious joke.

Harry rolled his eyes after Lockhart resumed walking. Then he smirked, pulled a book from his pouch, sat down, and began reading. He surreptitiously pressed his wand against a scrap of parchment he'd dropped a moment earlier.

Ginny frowned, "Are you forfeiting?"

"No, I'm still here."

"But you aren't ready. You aren't even standing up."

"Just do what you've got to do."

"But that's not a fair fight."

"I know, you never had a chance. Blame Lockhart."

Ginny scowled. As soon as Lockhart announced the beginning of the first match, Ginny cast a somnium while dodging. Harry ignored her and turned a page.

Ginny sighed and walked up to him, with her wand pointed at his head. Harry raised his arm in front of his face. Ginny called "Ma Ha Su", then yelped and dropped her wand.

Harry looked up, "That counts as a disarm."

Harry's next opponent introduced himself as Mike the Hufflepuff. Harry didn't remember him participating in an army the previous year and decided to stick with the same tactic. It was a calculated risk, as an upperclassman could potentially cast something that would win. But students hadn't seen Harry do anything impossible in a while and he felt it was past time to remedy that.

After Lockhart started the match, Mike immediately cast protego then expelliarmus. The bright pulse of magic struck Harry directly in the chest but reflected back exactly along its initial trajectory. While the magic flew back toward him, Mike tried to think of something better to cast while anticipating the spell dissipating against his shield. Unfortunately for him, it was his own spell, and he either forgot or didn't know to alter his shield harmonics. His wand flew across the room as his shield dropped.

Harry easily caught it and tossed it back, smiling.

Next, Cedric stood across from Harry, "That's interesting; I've never seen a shielded cloak reflect curses like that."

Harry nodded, "It's a useful property of mutually perpendicular mirrors. Actually, one of the first experiments that muggles left on the moon-"

Cedric continued, "But I wonder what its overload limit is? I guess I'll have to find out the hard way. That should make this match more interesting, at least. And thanks for that; dueling younger students so far has just felt wrong."

Harry smiled and stood up, "I don't think you'd have a problem overloading the shielding. Or dodging the ricochets. Even with the cloak, I know I can't beat you in a normal duel..."

Cedric's disappointment showed, "That's too bad."

Lockhart called the start of the third match and Cedric immediately cast a multi-layered protego shield. Harry gestured with his left hand, calling "Evard's Black Tentacles!"

Six tentacles sprouted from the floor inside Cedric's shield, wrapping around his torso, wrists, and angles, lifting him off the ground and pulling the wand out of his hand. Cedric exclaimed, "This isn't dueling." Harry simultaneously finished, "...so of course I wasn't going to fight a normal duel."

"That's not even a real spell", a nearby student interjected, appearing offended by the seeming violation of magical rules.

"Sure it is, you just watched me cast it. Maybe you should spend more time in the library. It was invented by the great wizard Gygax the Dungeon Master, and perfected for use in combat by Milo Naturalis-Viginti."

"Those aren't even real people!"

"You're going to tell me what in Merlin's beard that was, or we're going to have a problem", Cedric demanded after Harry let him down.

Harry walked over and lowered his voice, "That's what happens when I don't have to cast any spells for two matches in a row, when there's plenty of time to prepare a transfiguration. I transfigured this scrap into a thin, transparent layer covering the floor, then reshaped the part you were standing on into the tentacles."

"That's a massive transfiguration for a second year to shape that quickly even with the prep time. And more massive than you should have been able to hold for even fifteen seconds or so."

Harry smiled, "Not as massive as you'd think. They were inflatable, so I only transfigured the outer skin. Stretching and tensioning that skin made the tentacles move."

Lockhart loudly announced, "As you'd expect, many of these duels have been pretty one-sided. Let's try some closer match-ups. For example, we seem to have two undefeated second-year students. Harry and Draco, if you wouldn't mind stepping over here and giving us a demonstration."

The two students stepped into an empty area in the center of the room, while everyone else gathered around. They watched each other carefully.

Lockhart smiled, "Alright, ready... go!"

Draco didn't bother casting a shield, but instead quietly cast a variety of relatively harmless, low-powered spells as quickly as he could, with an occasional shield-breaker thrown in. Harry cast a stupify, which Draco easily side-stepped. Harry attempted to dodge most of the spells, but his cloak was able to reflect those he couldn't avoid.

Then Draco roared, "Serpentsortia" and a large constrictor landed about halfway between them. They continued casting spells and dodging as the snake shook itself off and began closing the distance toward Harry. Draco continued to conjure snakes whenever the opportunity arose, making them smaller and putting them closer to Harry each time.

Harry's room to move quickly decreased as the snakes surrounded him and closed in. Getting frustrated, he hissed, as quietly as possible, "go harasss the annoying blond child", while subtly gesturing at Draco.

As the snakes turned and moved away, Harry dove and rolled, came up casting a levitation spell, which he swept from left to right, catching Draco's legs and knocking him on his back. A follow-up somnium kept him there.

Harry let out a sigh and stood up then looked around and saw everyone staring at him. Over the silence, one quiet voice was audible, saying "Go away... Please go away." Everyone turned and saw the half-dozen snakes backing Luna into a corner. Neville quickly cast a series of sleeping spells until they stopped moving.

Lockhart called out, "Well, I think that's enough excitement for today. You should all get back to your common rooms for the night."

Gregory walked next to Draco and whispered, "You look surprisingly happy; you know you lost, right."

"Potter won the game he was playing and I won the game I was playing. But my game was better."

A few hours later, Vincent waved Daphne and Tracey into the room, "Mr. Malfoy was delayed. He should be here for the meeting in just a moment."

"Okay. Theodore and Millicent should be on their way from the common room."

Daphne walked in and sat down, while Tracey went to the desk, "Looks like Draco just started his homework for Transfiguration. I didn't picture him procrastinating more than I do."

"What are you doing?"

"Looking. Oh, Draco keeps a diary. I didn't expect that either."

"Stop snooping", Daphne hissed.

Tracey turned, pushing her bag behind her back and trying to make the movement look casual. She stuck her tongue out at Daphne, while slipping the diary into the bag.

"And stop acting like such a child."

"Fine." Tracey walked over and sat down next to Daphne, "Not being a child is boring. So, another Silvery Slytherins meeting. When is this group going to do anything interesting or useful, anyway?"

Daphne rolled her eyes, "If you don't understand it, why are you here? Anyway, it's important to improve the reputation..."

The next morning, a dead unicorn was found in the Forbidden Forest.

Chapter 12: One Level Higher

Note: some of the dialog in this chapter was inspired by/stolen from The 7th Horcrux (s/10677106)

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world, but has made significant progress: Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors. Progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities but a temporary solution is operational in the now-abandoned Azkaban tower.

Sprout received a cursed Hufflepuff Cup, and displayed uncharacteristically aggressive behavior afterwards. Moody detected evidence of dark magic on her but it was inconclusive. Since then, Moody has researched more specific spells for detecting horcrux effects and, as one might expect, Hermione tested positive. Draco found the Riddle Diary, and began plotting to amass power and followers for himself. Then Tracey 'borrowed' the diary.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. Bellatrix is still at large and able to appear in public despite topping Magical Britain's most wanted list.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and rescuing Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped, so he has focused more strongly on learning arithmancy, which involves putting spells together to achieve novel functions.

"Now come with me, help me to obtain the Stone, and I will resurrect Hermione Granger on your behalf. Her death has had unfortunate effects on you, and I would not mind undoing them."

Is he really going to do this? Really? There had to be a catch and Harry just couldn't see it. Voldemort had said that neither he nor any of his would harm Hermione, that her body and mind would be her own – why?

"There iss more work I intend to do, to give her besst chance of continued life. There iss old, losst ritual to ssacrifice magical creature, transsfer magical nature to ssubject. Limitationss are great. Transsfer iss temporary, only few hourss. Ssubject ssometimess diess when transsfer wearss off. But Sstone will make permanent. Girl-child sshall gain troll'ss power of regeneration. Transsfiguration ssicknesss iss nothing before that, if perchance it wass not fixed by previouss ritual. And no knife sshall sslay girl-child, nor cutting cursse, nor ssicknesss take her. Have not the tiniesst intention of letting girl-child die again, after going to ssuch lengthss to ressurrect her."

Harry swallowed. "I'm very confused." Was Voldemort practicing being nice? This hypothesis did not seem like a sufficient explanation. I'm seeing the Dark Lord Voldemort going to enormous lengths to resurrect Hermione Granger and keep her alive. It's like he thinks that his own life depends on Hermione Granger being alive, somehow.

"I would never want you to be deprived of Hermione Granger's counsel and restraint, not ever while the stars yet live. Thiss iss, indeed, horcrux of girl-child, my ssuperior verssion." In his other hand appeared a parchment. "Thiss iss ritual for ressurrecting her, if it musst be done again. Insstructionss are honesst, no trapss. Remember that girl-child'ss sspirit cannot float free like ghosst, Ressurrection Sstone iss my horcrux, not herss. Do not losse her horcrux, or her sspirit may be trapped within it."

The Dark Lord was now regarding Harry with a grim look. "When girl-child died, wass in company of sschool'ss Sseer, heard prophecy sspoken that you would become force of vasst desstruction. You would become threat beyond imagination, beyond apocalypsse. That iss why I went to ssuch lengthss to undo my killing of girl-child, keep it undone."

Harry's voice went up an octave, "I really really wouldn't do that, seriously!"

"Ssilence, fool. Remain ssilent unlesss given leave by me to sspeak. Keep your wand pointed down and do not raisse it unlesss told. Elsse you die upon the sspot, and mark that I ssaid that in Parsseltongue."

"Today we are doing Merlin's work, my Death Eaters. Yes! Before us stands a great danger, who in his blundering folly has been prophesied to wreak destruction such as even I can scarcely imagine. You will swear, Harry Potter, not to destroy the world, to take no risks when it comes to not destroying the world. Unless this very Vow itself is somehow leading into the destruction of the world, in which case, Harry Potter, you must ignore it in that particular regard. You will not trust yourself alone in making such a determination, you must confide honestly and fully in your trusted friend, and see if that one agrees."

Harry awoke from the nightmare, groaning loudly. He now understood that there was a terrible flaw in the vow Voldemort had designed: Hermione was a single point of failure. Astrophysics implied that the world would inevitably end. Dumbledore's final message implied that Harry would have to hasten its end in order to save humanity. That couldn't happen without Hermione's agreement, therefore she was just as necessary as he was to guarantee humanity's long-term survival.

Granted, Voldemort had made Hermione's death as unlikely as possible, but Earth's life expectancy was in the billions of years. Over that timescale, the normal definition of improbability becomes meaningless. And her death wasn't even the only apocalyptic scenario. Harry himself had become very dementor resistant, but didn't know whether Hermione was equally protected. And apparently it was also to suffer permanent psychological damage from the cruciatus curse or due to time-turner misuse. And of course, having a horcrux didn't protect someone from total obliviation.

Or did it? Harry had thought about that method of attack within a few hours of learning of the existence of Voldemort's horcrux network. How credible was the conclusion that Voldemort had never thought of it? Especially when the previous horcrux spell's explicit purpose was the preservation of memories.

Harry had no idea how memories propagated through the horcrux network. He had no reason to believe there weren't safeguards against passing obliviation or memory charms to the horcruxen. If putting his horcrux spell on the resurrection stone gave Voldemort the ability to call up his own ghost, would putting his horcrux spell on top of the original horcrux spell give him the ability to recover the memories in that horcrux? Same question for a vial containing a pensieve compatible memory.

Harry groaned again. Such a system, once in place, wouldn't be merely a safety device: it could be used deliberately. Occlumency involved allowing telepathy to reach a fictional mind, rather than the real one. Occlumency had won the arms race against legilimency and would even fool veritaserum. But was the status quo really that solid? Harry had wondered if wizards ever tried using a confundus, muggle drugs, or even sleep deprivation to prevent someone from retaining the mental discipline to create an occlumency barrier. What would happen if someone were obliviated of their occlumency training? And of course Parseltongue was immune to occlumency, as was the Mirror. Other artifacts, such as Sorting Hat or the Elder Wand, may share that ability. But obliviating or memory charming one's self permanently would have to successfully fool such things, because it would no longer really involve fooling them; the new memories would be the truth as far as the mind in question knew. So, with an advanced horcrux, Voldemort could memory charm his brain as necessary, effectively using his host as a higher level of occlumency barrier with the ability to fool methods intended to penetrate ordinary occlumency, then recover his previous memories from the horcrux.

That made everything Voldemort had said in Parseltongue suspect. Voldemort would likely have applied the minimum number of memory charms necessary to accomplish his goal, to minimize the chances of that physical iteration of himself doing something contrary to his real goals. The natural candidate was the alleged prophecy, because that single memory was allegedly the motive for most of Voldemort's actions that night.

Harry had extensively researched the nature of prophecies and learned that they almost never include proper names, or specific useful details like times or places. That Dumbledore had been using such things successfully... it would have been surprising if he'd done that without becoming a bit nuts. If Voldemort had heard a real prophecy, he should not have been so convinced that it was about Harry, rather than someone else, such as Voldemort himself. At the mirror, Voldemort had been certain that Dumbledore would put more value on Harry's life than on the combined outcome of preserving his own life plus defeating Voldemort. This implied that Voldemort had known about the prophecy Dumbledore had heard about Harry ending the world but not life. Therefore, Voldemort must have replaced his memory of that prophecy with a prophecy of his own invention after defeating Dumbledore.

So Voldemort had changed his own memory of the prophecies at play such that he would try to kill Harry. He'd probably also set himself up to make irrational mistakes, most notably allowing Harry to hold onto his wand. Perhaps the plan had been the same one Voldemort had articulated earlier: for Harry to publicly defeat Voldemort, securing good publicity and future political favor. But would Voldemort have been that certain that Harry could defeat a dumber but still dangerous Voldemort? That wasn't something he could've left to chance. So obviously, he didn't. He could've given one or more of the Death Eaters special orders, but that wouldn't have been enough. He could've had another host hiding nearby or even under one of the death-eater robes, just as he'd worn a white robe while fighting for SPHEW. Harry had watched him cast a powerful spell on Snape, the effects of which had never actually been explained.

It all made sense. Well, almost. It still left the original issue: why had Voldemort made some of Harry's future actions depend on Hermione's judgment? Actually, why revive Hermione at all? Was it just because Voldemort doing something out of character would help sell the prophecy story? And on the subject of 'in character', if Voldemort had feared Harry would end the world, wouldn't he have made Harry vow to obtain Voldemort's own assent before doing something risky? It's not like Voldemort would've cared if he was the single point of failure; if he were gone, he wouldn't have cared what else happened because his plan would've already failed.

Harry broke out in a cold sweat. Hermione had been surprisingly absent this school-year, spending an excessive amount of time alone either 'too busy' or 'too tired' to participate in various activities. To Voldemort, the only option better than forcing Harry to consult with him would be forcing Harry to consult with someone he trusted, but who was secretly controlled by Voldemort.

Before he could suppress it, a mental image came to Harry, showing Hermione find an empty room, cast a series of privacy charms, then sit quietly, drooling on herself. The troll strength and unicorn reflexes suddenly made sense: Voldemort wouldn't want to be trapped in a physically and magically weak body, so he provided some upgrades. And it explained the horcrux he made for her: it had made it impossible to check whether she was under the influence of Voldemort's horcruxen. She was the perfect host.

But Hermione was still alive. Azkaban proved that... assuming Harry could trust those memories; that Harry hadn't destroyed the dementors himself and then been obliviated. No, that was too paranoid. Her phoenix was proof. She was alive; he'd just need to find a way to exorcise an immortal dark wizard and she'd be fine.

A part of Harry interrupted this train of though and told himself not to panic; that he didn't have any real evidence for any of this. The rest of his mind acknowledged, then disregarded this thought; that was exactly what the wishful thinking part of his mind would say. And it just made so much sense. Either way, it was a scenario he needed to figure out a way to solve. Harry picked up his watch, checked the time, and thought for five minutes.

Harry sighed slowly. He wouldn't be able to tell anyone about any of this. Moody or Bones would want to permanently kill Hermione if they thought it would stop Voldemort's plan. Ignoring the obvious moral arguments, that was unacceptable because Hermione was necessary to humanity's future, and he didn't think they'd be able to appropriately weigh consequences that may not materialize for thousands or even millions of years. Not that they'd succeed anyway; if Harry told them and they reacted at all, the most likely outcome was that he would wake up obliviated of the last few days and Moody, Bones, and McGonagall would be dead.

Harry's best idea was to somehow find and destroy all of Voldemort's horcruxen without Voldemort realizing it and without Voldemort making new ones faster than Harry destroyed them. To call this impractical was an astronomical understatement; Harry's best... well, only... idea to accomplish this was to destroy the world and start over. Which would require Hermione's okay.

Harry didn't see any possibility of falling back asleep in the near future.

He sighed and decided to go out and watch the stars. He climbed the stairs from his office to the roof, cast a warming charm on himself, and laid on his back.

Some time later, he noticed an unexpected light in his peripheral vision and turned to identify it. He determined that it was coming from the astronomy tower a few seconds before the light went out.

Mildly curious, Harry got a broom and slowly approached the astronomy tower, navigating mostly by the outline of the castle against the sky in the moonless darkness.

"Hello, Harry."

"Oh. Hello, Luna. I guess I shouldn't be surprised that person out here at night turned out to be the one person I knew came out here at night."

"No, you shouldn't. It's more surprising that you're out on a broom at night. I don't think that's entirely safe."

"I flew slowly so it wouldn't have been too serious if I bumped into part of the castle. What else would be dangerous out here?"

"Dragons, for one. Or any especially annoyed hippogriffs. Or thestrals."

"I'll be sure to watch out for those. Although I don't think thestrals can actually fly."

"Unless that's what they want you to think."

"Huh. I'll have to look into it. Who's 'they'?"

"Yes. That's always the question... I suppose it's not surprising after all; flying out here isn't any more dangerous than your usual hobbies."

"You're going to have to explain that. Dangerous hobbies?"

"It's not a secret that you've been working with charmed objects. You should be more careful with them."

"Charming objects isn't normally considered dangerous."

"It depends on who charms them. That's how my mother died."

"Oh, I didn't know. I'm sorry about your mother."

"The aurors said she died researching spells because they didn't find any charmed objects nearby, but they're wrong. Her notes were vague and the aurors found a trace of unknown dark magic, so they assumed she cast something bad. But that was really from the artifact she found."

After a few minutes of platitudes and silence, Harry asked, "So, are there any astronomical objects you specifically wanted to see tonight? Recently, I've spent more time looking for satellites. It's nice, while I'm here in magical Britain, to get a visual reminder that there's a technologically advanced civilization nearby."

"It's nice to look at the stars and imagine being far away from here. Though I think I like watching the stars better here at Hogwarts. They're more alive here than I'm used to seeing."

"'Alive'? Last year, a centaur told me that they make predictions or prophecies or something based on how they see starlight flicker. Do you get information from the stars like centaurs do?"

"I don't know; I've never been a centaur."

"No, of course not; I meant... 'Being far away'? You think about getting away from here? Is something bothering you?"

Luna shrugged, "Many of the people here are less pleasant and enlightened than one would hope of intelligent magical beings."

Harry frowned, "Can you be more specific?"

"You don't need to worry about it. I suppose it's not that important in the big picture."

"If people are bothering you, at least that's a problem I know how to work with."

Luna nodded, "True."

It was still pre-dawn, but light was visible over the horizon when McGonagall's patronus came to Harry and announced an emergency meeting. He arrived at her office a few minutes later. McGonagall, Bones, Moody, and Hermione were already seated.

McGonagall explained quickly, "A unicorn has been killed. Mr. Hagrid is on his way to give us the details."

The seat at the end of the table facing everyone was clearly intended for Hagrid. The only other seat open was next to Hermione. Harry sat, carefully controlling his breathing as sensing her magical aura triggered his fight-or-flight response rather than the usual sense of comfort. He tried to neither look to his left, nor make it obvious that he was deliberately not looking.

Seconds later, the door opened again, admitting Hagrid and Lockhart. McGonagall waved Hagrid to the remaining chair.

Lockhart spoke first, "So the first thing we-"

Bones interrupted, "Why exactly are you here?"

Lockhart looked surprised but quickly recovered, "Uh... I'm the Hogwarts Defense Against the Dark Arts professor and you won't find anyone who has more extensive practical knowledge of or broader experience with dangerous magical creatures. I happened to overhear some things about the current situation, so when I happened to run into Hagrid on his way here, I thought my expertise would be appreciated."

Bones shook her head, "Mr. Hagrid, please have a seat, and tell us what happened."

"So I got up to walk Fang and feed the thestrals this morning-"

Moody asked, "About what time was that?"

"Maybe 5:00? Thestrals like to eat while it's still dark, so I always bring them-"

Bones interrupted, "Okay, let's skip ahead. When did you first notice something wrong?"

"Well, Fang started barking and ran off, but he does that sometimes. Aren't many things in the forest that scare old Fang. Anyway, I was following him, and I that's when I saw some silvery reflections on the ground. I could tell right away what it was, and knew Fang had found a unicorn, either hurt or dead. When I caught up with him, it was terrible. Another unicorn mostly eaten, just like last year."

Moody stared at Hagrid, "What are the chances your pet killed the unicorn?"

Hagrid's head snapped around to look at Moody, startled, "Huh?... Oh, Fang would never do such a thing. For one thing, he's well fed and doesn't need to hunt. For another, he'd never catch a unicorn. They're too fast for him."

McGonagall asked, "Hagrid, what do you suspect was responsible?"

"Er... nobody ever caught what was eating them last year. It's probably back, right? I never saw the sense of bringing in so many unicorns this year, with whatever it was still out there, but I figure Dumbledore must've had a plan."

McGonagall tried again, "How many things are even capable of taking down a unicorn?"

Lockhart jumped in, "I suspect a nundu. Coincidentally, I've been looking forward to hunting one for quite some time, and am familiar with all the latest literature on the most effective tactics. I'd be happy to lead a group of..."

He trailed off as he became aware of Moody staring at him intensely. After a few seconds of silence, Moody spoke, "There's never been a nundu attack in Britain. As far as anyone knows, there's never been a nundu in Britain." Lockhart nodded and opened his mouth to speak, but Moody demanded, "Did you bring one here?"

Lockhart shut his mouth quickly, paused, then answered, "Of course not. Someone would have to be totally irresponsible, or a complete idiot, to bring such a dangerous animal near a school." He smiled at Moody, "And of course, if I could work with those animals so easily, I'd have written about it. My skill as a nundu-whisperer would be common knowledge across the magical world."

"Are you directly or indirectly responsible for the death of any unicorns?"

"No! Of course not."

Moody grunted, but continued to watch Lockhart.

McGonagall repeated, "Hagrid, what would be fast enough to catch a unicorn?"

"Well, the fastest things out there are the phoenix and the dementor, b-"

"Things that would take a bite out of a large animal", Bones snapped.

"Well, a nundu would, of course. Or a quintaped. And I suppose a hydra or dragon or occamy."

McGonagall sighed, "Anything that would live around Hogwarts?"

"Well, I a centaur could probably hunt one, not that they ever would. I don't know, maybe if a hippogriff got hungry enough... Those things are quick in a powered dive. Maybe a troll or a werewolf. I don't know that they could outrun one, but they might be able to trap one somehow. Though it's the wrong moon phase for werewolves."

Lockhart interjected, "If a unicorn were injured somehow, or trapped, for example in a devil's snare or acromantula web, any number of things could finish it off."

Hagrid nodded, "Or I suppose a large snake could ambush one, though not many reptiles would be out hunting before spring."

Harry queried, "Not many or not any?"

Hermione turned to Bones and Moody and asked, "How sure are we that an animal was involved? I've read that dying dark wizards will often try to kill unicorns for their blood."

Hagrid frowned, "I don't think they'd take large bites. Something was eating it."

Harry processed the simultaneous series of objections that arose, which resolved into a decision to remain silent. Fortunately, or unfortunately, Moody stated, "Unless a dark wizard were covering up their activities."

Bones added, "Or if it were scavenged after it died. Mr. Hagrid, have you seen anything else unusual in the forests? Specifically anything that would indicate the presence of someone who doesn't belong there?"

"Well, the Forbidden Forest is never quite the same as the last time you saw it, but I haven't seen anything I'd call unexpected. I certainly haven't seen any dark wizards out there."

Bones concluded, "Okay, thank you Mr. Hagrid, you may go."

As Hagrid stood and moved to the door, Lockhart walked forward, clearly intending to take the vacated seat at the table. The chair twisted in on itself and disappeared before he reached it.

Bones stared him down, "You may go, Mr. Lockhart." He reluctantly walked through the doorway and the door shut itself behind him.

Bones sighed, "So I assume we all agree that this is Voldemort's doing, correct?"

Harry replied, "Well, it could be something else..." He trailed off and sighed upon seeing everyone else nodding in agreement with Bones.

Moody asked Harry directly, "Is there anything else we should know, Potter?"

"Well, if Voldemort is killing unicorns, it means he needs unicorn blood, which implies his body, I mean his host's body, is dying. If we assume he was possessing Professor Sprout earlier this year, then he has the ability to move from person to person somehow. He claimed he could use the Resurrection Stone to move around as a ghost and possess anyone he wanted, but at the time he was trying to convince me that he'd immediately return if I killed him. Otherwise he would need someone to find a horcrux in order to possess them. Anyway, if he's already moving between hosts, unicorn blood would be redundant and killing unicorns would unnecessarily reveal his presence." As he said it, the thought completed in his head: unless Voldemort suspects we already know he's here, and killed the unicorn just to give the impression that he needed its blood. Everyone would falsely conclude he had a weakness and was not, in fact, using a host whose blood already incorporated unicorn healing factors.

Moody asked, "So what's our next move? Voldemort could be possessing anyone."

"Surely he'd be more likely to possess some people that others", Bones argued. "A dark wizard would be most likely to possess a teacher, due to their higher magical strength and their privileges with Hogwarts' wards."

"Unless that constraint made finding him too obvious", Moody retorted.

Bones answered, "In that case, he'd want to possess someone with as much magical power and muscle strength as possible (which implies a 6th or 7th year with experience dueling, etc.). A wealthy family, noble or politically connected would also be useful in case he were caught doing something illegal."

Hermione suggested, "That could mean Cedric Diggory or Robert Jugson. I've heard Jugson has been acting strangely this year, though that could be explained by his... incident... earlier this year."

Moody looked unimpressed, "So that's even easier to narrow down than assuming he's using a professor."

Harry shrugged, "A smart dark wizard might play at the next level and deliberately choose someone as weak as possible, like a first year; just to do the opposite of what we'd expect. And a smarter dark wizard might choose someone as average as possible; someone whose name most of us wouldn't even know. But strength, skill, and money would still be valuable, so they'd choose between a more average or above average individual based on how much they intended to hide or to fight. In that case, we could rule out anyone below average. Though a dark wizard operating at the level above that may deliberately pick someone below average to escape that scrutiny."

"So basically it could be anyone", Moody repeated.

Harry sighed, "Yeah."

Moody continued, "We need to search the school; try to find his horcrux."

McGonagall sighed, "The school is huge and someone could easily lose something here for years."

Bones added, "It would also give away what we know; make it obvious that we're looking for something."

Moody nodded, "Okay, I propose that just before Christmas break, we tell everyone that there's an illness, a dragon-pox outbreak or something. So Pomfrey has to scan them before they go home, to prevent the disease from spreading. I'll polyjuice as Pomfrey and scan them for evidence of possession. Some disillusioned aurors can scan their luggage for dark magic. Then, after the students leave, we have some time for aurors to search the dorms, common rooms, offices, and commonly used classrooms. We can have the elves look everywhere else for anything that doesn't belong and bring it to the aurors."

Bones replied, "I can't imagine Voldemort being caught by something that easy, but it could reveal something."

McGonagall objected, "You're proposing to detect Voldemort in a group of students. There won't be any way to keep students safe when he starts fighting."

Moody nodded, "Of course we wouldn't try to arrest him there; we'll signal aurors to follow anyone who tests positive and then call everyone to help bring him down."

Bones concluded, "That sounds like a good starting point. Moody, work out the details, and pick some aurors to learn the necessary detection spells. I think we're finished here for today."

Bones and Moody flooed away, Harry and Hermione walked toward the door. "Mr. Potter, a moment", McGonagall said.

Harry asked, "Okay. Actually, I've been meaning to ask you: Has Hogwarts ever been struck by lightning, or do you know of any spells that protect it from lightning?"

"What? I've no idea. Why would you want to know that?"

"It's the simplest reason I've thought of for why anyone to ward the castle in a way that affects electricity. Wizards wouldn't understand the physics behind what they were trying to accomplish, so such wards would likely be trial-and-error and do complex and unpredictable things, some of which would be helpful, and some of which would only cause side effects."

"As I said, I don't know what the castle does with lightning. Maybe it's protected somehow or maybe it just heals itself afterward. Anyway, I asked you here because I've heard you've been using Parseltongue in public, which I've warned you against doing. I suppose you may have thought out all of the possible outcomes in advance, and decided it was worth risking; is that the case? And if so, what were you hoping to achieve?"

"I don't believe anyone should have been able to hear me speak it. Well, except I accidentally let Draco hear it last year. But I didn't know Parseltongue was a thing at the time, so that shouldn't count."

"I've been informed that you were seen commanding several snakes to attack a student at Lockhart's dueling practice. Have I been misinformed?"

"Well, partially. There were quite a few snakes closing in on me, and I did tell them to leave me alone, but no one would have heard that. If I looked through the library, I'm sure I could find a dozen spells that would repel snakes just as effectively. And it's not like that would be a surprising thing for me to have done. Concluding that I have a rare snake-related ability wouldn't be rational. And I certainly didn't command snakes to attack anyone."

Harry's eyes widened in sudden comprehension, "Draco sicced those snakes on me. He planned that. He must have had people start a rumor that I'm a parselmouth too. Of course, that's no excuse. It was just a school exercise, and I should have let myself lose."

"Then why didn't you?"

"I don't have a good answer for that. I thought I'd learned that lesson after the first few times, but apparently it's something I still need to work on."

Tracey strode into the Great Hall, eyes bright, head held high, and a hint of a smile on her face. She walked just quickly enough for the black cloak she wore over her robes to trail behind her like a cape.

Reaching the Slytherin table, she looked around suspiciously, then announced to the nearby second years, "Dumbledore is a far greater dark lord than I could ever hope to be. He's always fifty steps ahead of everyone else, so far ahead that once his enemies realize what his plan is, it's usually too late. Our best hope is to throw him off balance by planning zero steps ahead."

Gregory frowned, "Uh, Dumbledore's gone."

"Or that's just what he wants you to think. I'm going to be ready for him."

Pansy shook her head, "What is wrong with you?"

Vincent grunted in agreement and added, "You were already annoying. When did you become a morning person too?"

Tracey pointed at Pansy, "I've already taken your soul, but don't think that's the worst I can do to you. I could break you and rebuild you into a loyal minion, but I doubt you're useful enough for it to be worth the effort. Though I suppose I could lock you up and ransom you back to your family if you remain annoying. Be gone from my sight."

Pansy stared at her for a second, then got up and walked away.

After she was out of earshot, Daphne laughed, "Okay, that was pretty good."

Tracey turned to Daphne and declared, "So, you wish to join me. Your foresight is commendable, and I assure you that, if you choose to be my minion, you shall share in my eventual glory."

Daphne scoffed, "I'm a Greengrass. Greengrasses are not minions."

Tracey frowned, "You will come to rue this day, in time."

Theodore grumbled, "You're seriously not going to play Dark Lady Tracey again this year are you? I was hoping you'd outgrown that."

"Quiet, you. I will destroy your soul."

Theodore rolled his eyes, "I was in Chaos Legion, remember? We were the ones who helped you prank Pansy the last time. You can't use the same prank on me."

Daphne changed the subject, "You were in the common room late last night. When did you go to sleep?"

"Oh, I didn't sleep. I had more important things to do, you know."

"Then how are you even awake right now?"

Tracey waved dismissively, "I've grown beyond such mundane concerns."

"Seriously."

"I cast innervate on myself whenever I got tired."

"I don't think that's a good idea. Humans need sleep."

"Yes, and I think we've all established that I'm better than that."

Blaise announced, "Shh, he's here."

They turned to watch Harry enter the hall. A small group of snakes followed him.

Millicent shook her head, "It's like he's not even trying to keep people from thinking he's evil anymore."

Tracey agreed, "I fear that Harry may be the most evil of us all. That is concerning since I am the next Dark Lady."

Blaise chuckled, "Compared to him, you're an amateur. But you could ask if he's looking for someone to be his sidekick slash comic relief."

Tracey snapped, "You'll learn the consequences of such insolence." She then looked thoughtful, "But somehow you managed to include a decent point in your stupid comment, so I'll show you mercy for now. I should propose an alliance with Harry. For that to work out in my favor, I think I'm going to need some liquid luck. Does anyone have any blackmail material on Felthorne?" She looked around expectantly. "No? I guess we'll have to invent some."

Tracey looked around again, while no one volunteered suggestions. She looked briefly at Draco, then turned to Daphne. She opened her mouth to say something, then stopped and stared at Draco for another moment before turning back again. "Oh Merlin, I'm pretty sure Lucius managed to clone himself. I wonder if he knew a spell to transfer his memories into the clone too?"

Daphne replied, "I'm... Wait, what?"

Draco looked over at Tracey and growled.

Blaise stared at Draco, amused, "Did you just growl?"

Draco grunted.

"Grunting from a Malfoy? I'm shocked. You're lucky your father isn't around anymore." Draco scowled at Blaise and began to stand up. "By the 12th ruling of the 31st Wizengamot, if he saw you acting like this he could have disowned-"

Draco vaulted onto the table, then dove across, tackling Blaise onto the ground and throwing punches at his head.

A series of stunners from multiple directions quickly ended the fight. McGonagall and Flitwick hovered them out of the hall.

Tracey announced, "Blinding fury is not conducive to good decision-making. I think I'll hold off on offering Draco a chance to become one of my minions."

Chapter 13: Shell Game

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world, but has made significant progress: Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors. Progress toward a functional Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities but a temporary solution is operational in the now-abandoned Azkaban tower.

Sprout received a cursed Hufflepuff Cup, and displayed uncharacteristically aggressive behavior afterwards. Moody detected evidence of dark magic on her but it was inconclusive. Since then, Moody has researched more specific spells for detecting horcrux effects and, as one might expect, Hermione tested positive. Harry has begun to suspect something darker: that Voldemort's plan had been to pretend to fail while preparing a powerful and immortal host for himself who Harry would trust implicitly (and explicitly, given the unbreakable vow).

Draco found the Riddle Diary, and began plotting to amass power and followers for himself. Then Tracey 'borrowed' the diary. Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. Bellatrix is still at large and able to appear in public despite topping Magical Britain's most wanted list.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and rescuing Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped, so he has focused more strongly on learning arithmancy, which involves putting spells together to achieve novel functions.

Harry entered the Great Hall, trying to ignore the group of snakes gathering behind him. He sat at the Ravenclaw table and began filling a plate with food. All nearby conversations had stopped as people stared at him, but Harry chose to ignore that too.

Anthony looked around at the others, and seeing no reaction, spoke first, "All right, I'll be that guy. Harry, what's with the army of snakes? How worried should we be?"

Harry sighed, "I don't know. I don't know where they came from. I don't know why they're following me. I don't know what they'd be doing if they weren't following me. But I do know that if I tell them to leave me alone, everyone will blame me for whatever they do afterwards. I didn't ask them to follow me around, but it's almost certainly safer for everyone if they stay near me than if they go anywhere else."

After a few minutes, Harry asked the students nearby, "Does anyone know about anyone who's been bothering Luna?"

Terry scowled, "What do you care? You set snakes on her."

Harry rolled his eyes, "Do you actually believe that? For what possible reason would I have done that?"

Terry shrugged, "Who knows what you're planning? Maybe it was a misdirection so next week you can send snakes after, I don't know, Justin and no one will suspect you."

Harry shook his head, "That's insane. How would making people suspicious of me make people less suspicious? And why would I attack Justin?"

"I don't know! Why'd you attack Luna?"

Harry shook his head again, "Your argument is circular."

"Well, your argument is too thin."

"What does that even mean?"

"This conversation still means something? I thought we were just saying words now."

Around this time, they had both noticed that everyone else was silently staring across the room. Harry turned to see Draco and Blaise fighting. As McGonagall and Flitwick carried them out, Harry quickly got up and moved after them. The snakes followed.

Tracey saw Harry and moved to intercept, "Hey, Harry! I'm formally offering you a position in my Darke (with an 'E'!) Army. Once we've taken over, you can be the leader of... um, Hogsmeade."

Harry looked at her and forced a serious expression, "I think I'll hold out for a better offer."

"That was just my opening. There's room for negotiation. What would you be expecting?"

"I'll start getting interested when you stop talking about cities and start talking about continents. And important positions in the world government."

"There is no world government."

"I thought you wanted to be a Dark Lady."

Tracey nodded, "You're right of course. And I assume you're looking for something more than Antarctica. There are probably about as many people living in Hogsmeade as there are living there. How does South America sound? And, um, Minister of Global Muggle Affairs?"

Harry frowned, "I was thinking more of Minister of Health, Science, and/or Magical Research... There are wizards in Antarctica?"

"I used to have a pen pal there. It sounds great, actually: there's only one little spot where you have to worry about the Statute of Secrecy at all. And there's no age limit for wands or any underage magic rules. Anyway, I'm willing to promise you all of those positions, and not just because you're the only one who would both want them and be competent to do them."

Harry nodded thoughtfully, "That makes sense. Of course, before I commit to anything, I'll have to see your ten-year plan."

"Ten... years...?"

Harry nodded again, "Honestly, I have some doubts about your commitment. You can't take over the world without a well thought-out plan."

"Do you have a ten-year plan?"

Harry shrugged, "I've got the high-level outline. Many of the details are still hazy. It's my hundred-year plan that needs work. It's even less detailed than my thousand-year plan."

"Thousand-year? So you've found a way to become immortal?"

"I know there are some methods out there. I'm confident something will be available to me when I need it."

"Part of our plan should be to find all the spells and artifacts related to all of those methods as soon as possible. After all, one can never be too immortal."

"That's very true", Harry agreed. "Anyway, I'm going to go find out what's going on with Draco. You didn't happen to notice anything before he went postal, did you?"

"Hm, I was pondering if he were a clone of Lucius and the corollary of whether Lucius might have figured out a way to transfer his mind or memories into a clone. And I suppose he was less verbal than usual."

"Oh... Okay, I'll look into it."

Tracey looked around, and muttered quietly, "Neville... he could definitely be useful." She thought for a moment, then walked over, "Merlin bless the simple interactions of Hufflepuffs."

"Neville", she said sweetly, "Do you want to be friends?"

"Uh, sure. Assuming we weren't already..."

"One condition. You have to swear a magical oath that you will never, ever harm me no matter what I do."

Neville looked mildly surprised, "What?"

Tracey burst into laughter. "Just kidding! Anyway, do you know any of the details of Harry's plan to take over the world?"

He frowned, trying and failing to determine the nature of the conversation that had been inflicted on him.

Before he could form an answer, Tracey announced, "Kidding again!" and walked away quickly.

Neville shook his head, "I'll never understand girls."

When Harry reached the medical wing Moody was already scanning Draco. Draco awoke and Moody paused and stared down at him.

After a few seconds Draco yelled, "The Wizengamot will have you in Azkaban when they find you've used legilimency on a me!"

"Yeah, I very much doubt that."

"They would never tolerate someone violating the mental privacy of a member of a noble house!"

Moody turned to McGonagall, "No evidence of dark magic, but he's had a huge number of memory modifications. Multiple charms per day over at least the past month."

Draco began, "I demand-"

"Mr. Malfoy", McGonagall interrupted, "You have been memory charmed by an unknown individual for an unknown purpose. I would think you would want to know what is going on and to have Auror Moody hunt down whoever is responsible."

"For all I know, Moody is the one applying memory charms. I'll-"

"I assure you that he did not. This was the act of a criminal who has ill intentions toward you and likely toward the school as well. The Hogwarts board of governors will not tolerate an agent of a dark wizard with an unknown agenda to stay at Hogwarts. If you don't allow Auror Moody to determine the nature of those memory charms, you will not be allowed to remain here."

"If you think I'm going to allow Dumbledore's followers access to my mind-"

Harry interjected, "Does it have to be Moody? If that's the issue, we could find someone neutral, like Mr. Bester."

"And why would you suggest him, Potter? A secret alliance-"

"Petrificus totalus", Moody suddenly cast. "Stupid wanker just tried to draw on me." Moody gestured at Draco's hand, which was frozen in the act of pulling a wand from his robes. "No one searched him for a second wand? Well, luckily now he's awake, has his eyes open, and can't refuse legilimency." Moody began staring into Draco's eyes before Harry or McGonagall could react.

A moment later Moody reported, "The last memory charm takes place in Hogwarts... and depicts the killing of Abigail Myrtle... He cast a spell first and then some kind of magic transfered to whatever he was holding... He never looked at it, but it feels fairly light and has a flat bottom... Stupify."

Draco's eyes became unfocused but he didn't move otherwise.

They followed Moody into another room, where he cast a set of privacy charms. Then a charm which made the snakes following Harry immolate. "I don't trust those things; I don't trust magical constructs in general, and there's no reason for those to be here. Also, you look ridiculous leading a flock of snakes like some demented Slytherin shepherd. Anyway... Someone was memory charming Draco to think he was Voldemort. And they knew what they were doing; that memory was consistent with what I know of the horcrux ritual."

McGonagall frowned, "So you think Voldemort wanted us to believe Draco was possessed?"

Harry answered, "This actually sounds consistent with the basic horcrux spell (which is almost certainly what Moody is familiar with). It involves a device that stores memories and writes them into the victim's mind. The result is less of a possession and more of a hybrid personality, which gradually becomes more similar to the dark wizard as their memories are merged. The advanced horcrux ritual involves something more like possession but is more secret, so it's unlikely Moody has read any description of it."

Moody sighed, "So we might have a horcruxed wizard (who would seem to be under the imperius) using memory charms on Draco, a horcruxed wizard (who appears to be memory charmed) using the imperius on Sprout, or two Voldemorts with totally different abilities and possibly different plans and goals?"

"I believe that's an accurate summary of our current level of ignorance. But Occam's Razor suggests we assume one agent is responsible until we have evidence otherwise, and all of the advanced horcruxen should have been obliviated along with Voldemort", Harry gestured at the ring, "so I'd bet on option 2. But our response is pretty much the same regardless: find and destroy a horcrux. I suggest we proceed as if it were an outbreak: quarantine everyone who shows symptoms (in this case, violent behavior, evidence of dark magic, or evidence of memory charms), and check everyone they had close contact with for symptoms."

Daphne sighed, "Tell me again: why are we sneaking into the library at night?"

Tracey smiled brightly and gestured with the diary she was carrying for emphasis, "I told you; there's information there that's critical to the fulfillment of my master plan for world domination."

"No, really... This is the forbidden section! You're seriously breaking into the forbidden section? That's kinda over the line, even for you."

"Let me tell you a story: this morning I was talking to General Chaos. It started as just a typical dark lady-dark lord discussion about taking over the world and stuff. But then, suddenly he almost had me convinced that I'm in over my head here. Of course, that tricky reverse-psychology stuff only works on the weak-minded, and it was sloppy of him to try a plot like that on me. But regardless, decisive action is required."

"If you stop and think for a second-"

Tracey waved dismissively and pulled a pair of books off the shelf, "Stop thinking like a Hufflepuff. When I rule this world, I will give you first pick of countries to control."

Daphne sighed again.

Tracey smirked and muttered, "No one wants to be a Hufflepuff." She pulled another book off the shelf and flipped through it quickly, almost dropping the others in the process. She then stacked the four books on the floor and walked down the aisle, pulling another few texts off the shelf.

Daphne sighed and watched the doorway.

Tracey added another armful of books to the pile and continued browsing. As Tracey disappeared down another aisle, Daphne heard footsteps echoing down the hallway and held her breath.

The footsteps were getting closer. Daphne looked around, trying not to panic, wishing for some solution to manifest itself. If this were a battle, her next step would be... to hide the evidence and escape. She stepped forward, tucked Tracey's pile of books under her left arm and quickly moved in the direction Tracey had disappeared.

Once she, and the evidence, were out of view of the doorway, Daphne started to feel more confident. She frowned as Tracey walked toward her carrying another pair of books, then scowled as Tracey loudly announced, "Guess what I fou-"

"Somnium", Tracey fell. Daphne smirked, knowing that whoever was coming would probably stop searching after finding an unconscious student.

"Obliviate", Daphne frowned. She didn't remember learning to cast that spell. She shrugged to herself; this was no time to be solving mysteries.

She put down the stack of books and cast 'quietus' charms on her hands, shoes, and mouth. She put a hand on the shelf but paused and returned to the stack of books. She pulled out the bottom book; it was the diary Tracey had been carrying everywhere since she'd stolen it from Draco. She shook her head, then paused in the motion of putting it back. She was strangely hesitant to leave it behind. She carried it with her as she climbed the bookshelf and lied flat on the top. A moment later, McGonagall entered the library and moved toward the restricted section.

As McGonagall walked around the bookshelf, Daphne climbed down the opposite side and silently sprinted down the hallway.

McGonagall quickly approached Tracey, noted the pile of books, and cast 'innervate'.

Tracey rubbed her eyes and sat up, "Oh, hello, headmistress. What's..." She looked around, "What happened?"

"That was my question. Why are you here?"

"I don't remember."

"What's the last thing you remember?"

"Leaving Charms class."

"Friday afternoon? You don't remember any of Friday evening or Saturday?"

"Oh... that sounds like something I wouldn't have expected until I was older... Although drinking butter-beer and sneaking around at night does sound fun. I'll be annoyed if that happened and I forgot about it."

"We're going to see Madame Pomfrey. She'll figure out what happened."

McGonagall concluded, "...so now Tracey has been obliviated. I suspect it's the same as what happened to Draco, but whoever is responsible has started trying to cover their tracks."

Moody grunted, "So we can conclude it's a professor. Call Lockhart in here and I'll get some answers."

"Actually, the wards recorded an unauthorized obliviation, so it's most likely not..."

She was interrupted as one of the objects in the office emitted a high pitched siren. McGonagall tapped it with her wand and it became silent. "There have been two more unauthorized obliviations near the Great Hall."

They simultaneously moved toward the door.

Daphne casually walked toward the Gryffindor table, tapped Lavender's shoulder, and whispered, "I need to talk to you. Wait about 30 seconds and then follow me. I'll be just outside the doors."

A moment later, Lavender bounded excitedly through the doorway and whispered, "Is it a secret mission? We haven't even a quest yet this year, not even a boring or easy one. Will it be dangerous? Or will-"

"Confundus", Daphne pushed the diary into Lavender's hands. Lavender turned and walked back into the hall. A moment later, she returned, empty-handed.

The girls raised their wands at each other and simultaneously cast, "Obliviate."

After a moment, they blinked and looked around, then turned back to each other.

"What in Merlin's hat just happened?"

"Where did you come from?"

"I think my stomach just magically filled itself with food. Is that a real thing?"

"How did I get here? Actually, what day is it?"

McGonagall and Moody, who had arrived in time to catch part of this quasi-conversation, exchanged glances and escorted the girls to the hospital wing.

Harry paced back and forth in his office. Despite nearly a dozen disillusioned or polyjuiced aurors present, and nearly all of the aurors in Britain prepared to time-turn to provide backup, it was still too dangerous for him to personally observe the hostile wizard detection and containment exercise (as Mad-Eye had termed the effort to scan the students for legilimency, memory charms and possession as they left for the train). He had to hide out here and wait for the results. And he'd been unable to convince anyone that Hermione should remain at Hogwarts over the break (the argument that she hadn't seen her parents in nearly a year had proven superior to anything he could make himself say out loud), so he strongly suspected he knew what the results would be.

Harry was convinced that Voldemort, while possessing Hermione, was pretending that one of his old type1 horcruxen was loose in the school, in order to cover up his actual presence and distract from his real plan. At some point, he could produce a fake (or real) type 1 horcrux and allow it to be discovered and destroyed, thereby apparently ending the current emergency. So far, this faux-crux had allegedly affected Draco, then Tracy, then Daphne (who's memory had been wiped back to before Tracey had been obliviated), then Lavender. Therefore it was likely that someone who knew Lavender (and probably also Daphne) would show traces of memory charms or obliviation. Maybe this person would even have a suspicious artifact (which would likely be destroyed before it could be carefully scrutinized). After that, there would be no more suspicions (except from Mad-Eye, who was suspicious of everything on principle), and Voldemort would be able to continue operating freely with his super-powered host.

Chapter 16: HPMoR Origins: Reflections on Atlantis (Omake)

Aurelius giggled to himself, anxiously waiting for his sister Julia's return.

"Aurelius!"

He involuntarily jumped and screamed, wishing, not for the first time, that apparition made some sound to announce a person's arrival. "Uncle Marcus. What are you doing here?"

"What am I doing here? What are you still doing here? You should have been evacuated by now."

Aurelius frowned, "I'm not an idiot. Atlantis is the safest place in the world. And this is Loki's Day. I know a prank when I see one."

"Loki does not deserve a holiday. If he ever comes back from Scandinavia, he'll be locked up for..."

Aurelius flinched as Marcus muttered a string of very bad words, which don't translate well but are a few syllables short of completing a very illegal torture curse. "Half of Atlantis has been destroyed with hundreds dead, and somehow Loki's still responsible. They all must have assumed the danger was just a joke...I need to find Antonius. Where is he? Or Cornelia?"

"Mom and dad both had meetings scheduled all day. They're not supposed to be back for hours."

"Well, let's go find them."

A moment later, they had arrived in the apparation room of the Atlantean capitol building. Walking down the main hallway, they quickly realized that the building was deserted.

"What exactly-" The sound of a muffled explosion interrupted Aurelius' question. A slight tremor shook the floor.

Marcus hesitated, then moved quickly to the staircase. "Hopefully someone is still in the command room."

As they ran up the stairs, another explosion shook the building, almost sending them back down.

They emerged into the command room. Through the windows, which provided a clear view of the entire city, Aurelius could see that his uncle had not been joking. To the south there was a large void, like a wide, shallow crater, extending from the nearby towers into the distance. Many of the buildings nearby were engulfed in an unnatural purple flame.

The next explosion threw them to the floor. When they got back up, the room was filled with a bright purple glow; the fire had spread to the outside of the tower.

Marcus muttered another curse, then added, "That's it, I'm going to use one of the Wands of Power."

Aurelius looked at him, shocked, "You're not allowed to do that."

Marcus walked toward a table with four stone boxes on it in the center of the room. "Look around. The Central Court is in flames and the council appears to have fled. There are no laws at the moment and someone has to do something..." He tapped one of the boxes with his wand. "Dammit. The Wand of Preservation and Invincibility is gone. I could've used that to cast a protection ward over the surviving parts of the city... The Wand of Creation and Life and the Wand of Change are also gone..." He sighed in relief, "Not my first, second, or third choice, but at least the Wand of Death and Destruction is still here."

"Um... how is that going to help?"

"It shouldn't be difficult. I'll ask it to conjure an army of something capable of eliminating the threat." Marcus picked up the blacker-than-black wand and closed his eyes to concentrate.

A moment later, the room filled with dozens of cloaked figures. Marcus lowered the wand and the figures quickly flew out the windows in all directions. The room dimmed as the flames froze and fell away.

Aurelius shivered, "Those things look evil. Why do they have to look like that? Were you trying to make flying corpses? Are you sure they're not worse than- What exactly are we fighting?"

Marcus sighed, "Some kind of magical fire zebras, apparently."

Aurelius turned pale, "Zebras?"

"Yeah, does that mean something to you?"

"No, that was just a prank! It's Loki's Day!"

"Aurelius, what did you do?"

"Julia's started studying wandless magic..."

"Get there faster."

"After some of the beginner stuff, I added a page with a spell that conjures a zebra. And a page after it with the instruction to use the spell 'geminullus' to dispel it. The description noted that some emotions, like surprise or frustration, prevent that spell from functioning correctly. She was supposed to spend all day chasing the zebra through the city trying to dispel it with a fake spell."

Marcus immediately grabbed Aurelius' arm and apparated south near the edge of the crater. "We have to look for your sister."

Aurelius looked around. The ruined buildings were caked with purple ice and there was a zebra corpse in every direction he looked.

Marcus exclaimed suddenly, "Dammit, your fake spell sounds close to 'gemino'. She must have been trying variants in the pronunciation. That could explain this."

"Multiple zebras I understand, but what about the fiery explosions?"

"'Gemino' normally conjures objects purely by magic, but a degraded form could make copies by reshaping nearby matter instead. Everything would be consumed; buildings, vehicles, even the ground itself. The sudden appearance of voids would sound like thunder and such a spell could easily release enough heat to start fires... Where would your sister have gone?"

Aurelius gestured, "She liked to practice in the park-" The rest of his answer was interrupted by apparating away. Marcus quickly cast a locater spell and they apparated away again.

They arrived a few blocks south of the park, and immediately found Julia. Her eyes were open, and she was breathing but unresponsive. Marcus cast a series of diagnostic spells then shook his head. "Nothing..."

"Nothing? I don't understand." Aurelius looked up at him, panicked, "She stopped breathing. Do something."

Marcus took three deep breaths, leveled his wand and commanded, 'resurrectus mira'.

"She's breathing again." Aurelius shook her shoulders, "Julia, wake up!"

"Please help me!" They spun to see a man running toward them, with a flying corpse closing in on him. He tripped on the uneven ground and it descended onto him. Marcus fired a series of blasting curses at it. It stared at him for a few seconds then flew off.

The man didn't move. Marcus cast the diagnostic spells on him, then shook his head, "It's the same thing." He pulled out the Wand of Death and stared at it for a moment. "No one should ever use this. Why would anyone even make it?", he asked, then snapped it in half and dropped it.

"Uncle, look", Aurelius pointed to one of the flying corpses, which had turned and started flying toward them. "And there's another."

Marcus quickly apparated them back to the capitol building, into a large storage room. "Try to find a chrono-apparation orb. I can fix this."

Aurelius questioned, "I know those let you apparate up to six hours forward or backward but you can't use them to change anything. How will that help?"

"The charms on the orb limit the user from doing those things. If I blast open the orb, I can release the Sands of Time within and use that magic directly. It's considered extremely dangerous, but I don't see how things could get any worse... Ah, here's one."

As he broke the orb, a flying corpse broke through the door. It dived and grabbed him just as he disapparated and both disappeared.

Aurelius suddenly found himself in a space made of white light. He was somehow able to watch the entire world below him. He saw that the monster had disrupted his uncle's control over time, so they had apparated much earlier than intended. That thing killed the founders of Atlantis as they were deep in meditation, channeling the magic necessary to conjure the island. By killing them, the flying corpse apparently absorbed sufficient magic to reproduce itself thousands of times. Aurelius briefly wondered whether anyone would even remember Atlantis or its magic. It had become the city that never was.

Aurelius noticed a doorway in front of him. On other side were his family members, Julia, Marcus, and his parents. He ran forward to meet them but fell after bumping into a glass... window? No, a mirror. He stood and found that he was somehow on the other side.

Julia smiled, "I got you this year."

Cornelia snapped, "Julia, apologize!"

She rolled her eyes, and recited in a monotone voice, "I'm sorry I trapped you in a magic mirror."

"What? How long have I..."

Julia smiled, "About a year."

Cornelia warned, "Julia."

She sighed, "Just 16 hours. It's less than you deserve for what you did last year. But at least you missed all of Loki's Day."

Antonius frowned, "Loki does not deserve a holiday. If he ever comes back from Scandinavia, he'll be locked up for a very long time."

Marcus smiled, "Now that all that's settled, let's go to Rome for dinner. They've recently invented something called 'pizza' that I think you'll enjoy."

As they turned to leave, Antonius turned back to the mirror, "Why is it still showing that world? Shouldn't it have stopped once no one was left inside the mirror?"

Cornelia shrugged, "Yeah, that's a little strange. I'll ask one of the experts about it tomorrow."

Marcus shuddered, "Naturally of all the worlds people have built in that mirror, that abomination with its soul-eating monsters and no Atlantis would be the one it decides to preserve."

Chapter 17: Bonus (Omake)

I've posted these things on Reddit, but I've decided to repost them here before they become lost to time. If you haven't read it, it's new to you.

A draft chapter from Harry's second year

Three students had been petrified. Petrified as in transfigured into stone. McGonagall announced that the transfiguration could be reversed safely with a potion, unfortunately that potion required some dangerous and rare ingredients that would take most of the school-year to prepare.

Draco's group, the Curious School Inquirers, who had taken it upon themselves to look into mysterious aspects of Hogwarts, had thus far been unable to find an explanation. Even Draco's new habit of carrying a muggle magnifying glass and wearing a deerstalker hat had proven insufficient to bring the situation into focus.

Harry tried, unsuccessfully, to convince Hermione to stop trying to confront the mysterious dark force. While a troll's auto-transfiguration would likely prove immune to the effect, Harry couldn't avoid the obvious parallels to his method of neutralizing Voldemort.

But, like Draco, Hermione had been unable to discover what was going on.

Harry decided to take a quick break from researching spells and artifacts that could cause petrification transfigurations, either as a primary goal or potential side effect, and look into alternate ways to help those who were affected. While being petrified for 6 months wasn't nearly the worst thing that could happen to someone, those students would ultimately have to repeat the year. Harry sympathized with being separated from familiar classmates and friends, given that, though he was taking second year charms and defense, he was taking 4th year potions, runes, and transfiguration and 6th year arithmancy. He began thumbing through some of the more obscure potions texts he had accumulated, looking for alternative cures.

Eventually, he found an arcane transfiguration reversal potion, based primarily around a magical plant known as a phoenix-feather reed, which needed to be harvested in a very specific, careful way in order to transfer its magical properties to the potion. The downside was that it wasn't guaranteed to work; the odds of successful transfiguration reversal were related to the weight of the reeds used in the potion, but it never got above 80%. Still, there were no obvious downsides, so Harry decided to pursue it. He discovered that those reeds grew among the plants around the shore of Hogwarts lake.

After talking to Professor McGonagall, Madam Pomfrey, and later, the entire school, he had a small army of volunteers to help. He made sure all of them knew how to identify the correct plant, and a smaller number knew how to correctly harvest it. The larger group of students cut down the weeds and tossed them into a pile, allowing the smaller group to access and careful harvest the phoenix-feather reeds. Harry, meanwhile, transfigured a thin layer of metal over a natural depression in the ground, creating a huge cauldron, and began preparing the rest of the potion.

After a few hours, Harry had the cauldron ready. The students had made their way around almost half of the lake and prepared a small bundle of plants for the potion, yet Harry calculated that it was only enough to give the potion a 10% chance of success. He made a noise of disgust, almost giving up on his plan. Then his eyes lit up, and he grabbed armful after armful of the non-magical plants, and tossed them into the cauldron.

Hermione saw what he was doing and yelled, "Harry, that's not what the instructions say. What are you doing?!"

"Isn't it obvious?" He replied, "The weeds of the many outweigh the reeds of the few."

originally posted at (HPMOR 314xg1)

After actually_just_idiot posted "And the mirror will be suspended above a fiery wasteland. Not because they moved it, that's just what Hogwarts became in Harry's 4th year." (at HPMOR 2y3gv2 cp5wfrf) and gameboy17 replied "Turns out a Hogwarts science fair was exactly as bad as his parents would have guessed. " (at cp5wm14):

If Hogwarts had a science fair...

Entry 41: Harry James Potter Evans-Verres, "Magical Artifacts Applied to Preliminary Terra-Forming"

Materials: one pair of vanishing cabinets, one phoenix

Theory: Mars has too little greenhouse gas to be habitable. Venus has too much. Obvious solution is obvious. Phoenixi are capable of near-instantaneous (it has yet to be determined how their speed compares to the speed of light) teleportation.

Procedure: The doors of both cabinets were removed, creating a stable wormhole between the two artifacts. A phoenix was instructed to put one cabinet on the planet Mars (this process took several days). After returning, the phoenix was given a few days off and then instructed to put the other cabinet on Venus.

Results: A phoenix can apparently only travel a few hundred million kilometers before regenerating; a limit that was previously unknown due to the fact that wizards have only used them for travel near Earth's surface, where the maximum travel distance is less than 13 thousand kilometers. This limit requires further experimentation to precisely determine.

Gas instantly began flowing from the high pressure atmosphere of Venus to the low pressure atmosphere of Mars. Currently, large vortical storm systems are centered around the cabinets on both planets. After the pressure equalizes, flow will stop and stage 2 (the selection and transplantation of appropriate extremophiles) can begin. I've been informed that NASA's planetary protection committee is very upset by the contamination of Mars and will likely oppose stage 2 as well.

Fawkes' current location is unknown. Due to the well-known regeneration abilities of phoenixi (and witnesses seeing him with the headmaster several times in the past few days), this researcher suspects he is hiding from me; apparently saving a phoenix' master from magical solitary confinement only goes so far for those ungrateful fire-chickens.

originally posted at (HPMOR 2y3gv2 cp5yhmt)

In response to someone who posted the title "Chapter 123 " with the text "Just kidding. " shortly after HPMoR concluded (at HPMOR 2z31zg):

Just for that, this is what you get:

Chapter 123: Futility

Harry awoke the next day, eager to eat breakfast and study with Hermione. As he arrived in the great hall, an owl arrived and presented him with a letter. He opened the envelope and frowned when he pulled out a second envelope. He began to tear open the inner envelope when he felt the pull of a portkey. "Dumbledore can't inspect and return my mail anymore", he realized. He landed in a small room, lit by a dim blue glow coming from nowhere or everywhere. There was only one door, and Harry walked over and opened it.

A sealed horror flowed out of its prison, snapping Harry's neck with two of its tentacles. It then began tunneling upward out of the room. Civilization didn't survive long after that.

Chapter 19: Recklessness, Pt 2

Here's how it is:

During his second year at Hogwarts, Harry is still concerned about the fate of the world and, though Hermione has obtained a phoenix and destroyed Azkaban's dementors, work on the Philosopher's Stone based hospital at Hogwarts has stalled due to ward incompatibilities and the temporary hospital in Azkaban tower has been shut down after being compromised by Bellatrix. Many aurors were killed or fatally injured and are in transfiguration-based stasis awaiting treatment.

Moody detected evidence of horcrux possession on Hermione and probably on Sprout. Draco and other students demonstrated unusual behavior and were later found to have been memory charmed. Harry thought of potential countermeasures Voldemort could have used against parseltongue and obliviation and suspects that Voldemort survived, that his plan had been to pretend to lose while preparing a powerful and immortal host for himself who Harry would trust implicitly (and explicitly, given the unbreakable vow). Unfortunately, that same vow prevented Harry from sharing his suspicions, until Moody revealed that he'd been thinking similar things. Thus far, efforts to locate a horcrux at Hogwarts have been unsuccessful.

Luna demonstrates uncanny knowledge even though she's obviously not a real seer. Moody has hypothesized that Defense professor Gilderoy Lockhart is incompetent and relying on liquid luck for his accomplishments. And obviously plotting something.

Harry has a relatively long list of things he intends to investigate, including big picture items like Merlin's Interdict, prophecy, time-turner paradoxes, magic-technology interactions, and rescuing Dumbledore, as well as smaller scale things like looking into Ravenclaw's Diadem or whether the potion liquid luck is a real thing or a cover story. Magical interferences with technology are proving more difficult to pin down than he had hoped, so he has focused more strongly on learning arithmancy, which involves putting spells together to achieve novel functions.

If you think hard enough you can do the impossible.

(It had always been an article of faith with Harry. There'd been a time when he'd acknowledged the laws of physics as ultimate limitations, and now he suspected there were no true limits at all.)

If you think fast enough you can sometimes do the impossible quickly...

...sometimes.

Only sometimes.

Not always.

Not reliably.

With Professor Flitwick gone, Harry had asked Professor Vector if there was any way to detect damage to the wards around the crystal cases, verify the residue that a real duel should have left behind. Harry had raced through the Hogwarts library looking for spells to tell the difference between old fingerprints and new fingerprints, or to detect lingering exhalations in a room. And all those attempts at playing detective had failed.

There were no clues, none that he was smart enough to find.

Professor Snape had said that the portkey led to an empty house in London, with no sign of anyone or anything else.

Professor Snape hadn't found any notes in Hermione's dorm.

Headmaster Dumbledore had said that Voldemort's spirit was probably hiding out in the Chamber of Secrets where the Hogwarts security system couldn't find him. Harry had snuck into the Slytherin dungeons under the Cloak of Invisibility and spent the rest of the afternoon looking through all the obvious places, but he hadn't found anything snaky that answered back when spoken to. The entrance to the Chamber of Secrets, it seemed, hadn't been meant to be found in a day.

Harry had talked to all of Hermione's friends that would still talk to him, and none of them had remembered Hermione saying anything specific about why she'd believed that Draco was plotting against her.

Harry had used up all six hours from his Time-Turner, and there were still no clues, and he had to go to sleep now if he wanted to be functional at Hermione's trial the next day.

The Boy-Who-Destroyed-A-Dementor was standing in the middle of the Hogwarts trophy room, his wand dropped at his feet.

He was crying.

Sometimes you call your brain and it doesn't answer.

After awaking, Harry sighed softly, then stunned himself back to sleep.

Harry stated, "Headmistress, I have a meeting with Arthur Weasley at the Ministry this morning, so I won't be in the castle for a while."

She nodded, "You think he can help you study how muggle artifacts work with magic?"

"Maybe, but I doubt it. I mostly wanted an excuse to see the Ministry of Magic without the Acting Chief Warlock thinking I'm checking up on her or something."

Sometime later, he flooed into the Ministry atrium. Harry had nothing to compare it to, but it looked to him like business as usual was occurring. Some people were standing around talking while others appeared to be in a hurry to go in various directions. A receptionist asked Harry why he was there and then provided directions to the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts office. Harry thanked him and walked away.

And then began exploring.

Harry walked through random hallway after random hallway. Harry quickly noted that the layout was more sensible than Hogwarts, the automatically supplied the phrase "damned with faint praise". Occasionally a doorway was labeled with a name he recognized from a newspaper or a conversation, but mostly the building was a large collection of anonymous offices. Harry had decided against walking into the Department of Mysteries without an appointment, but he couldn't resist visiting the Wizengamot chamber, that symbol of current political power and lost magical power, which was likely the reason why the Ministry of Magic was located in a densely populated muggle city. After standing behind the Chief Warlock's podium and looking down at the chamber, Harry paused for a moment, then checked his watch and moved toward the exit, backtracking and navigating the the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts office.

Harry knocked on the door of Arthur's office, and was quickly invited in, "Oh, Hello Harry. Sorry about the mess, I had to move everything in here so the DMLE could use my department's other rooms."

"Oh. I didn't notice anything wrong at all with the building, so I kind of assumed they'd already repaired everything."

"No, they just put up illusions in some hallways to hide the damaged areas. It's good enough to fool anyone who doesn't come here often; they don't want to look weak to representatives of foreign governments. Anyway, I've been looking forward to talking with you. I heard some things about how you were using muggle devices in those dueling sessions last year. Can you tell me a little more about that?"

Harry suppressed a sigh and began answering questions.

Sometime later, Arthur added, "It's too bad they made you stop. That's exactly the kind of thinking we need in the Department of Misuse of Muggle Artifacts. I don't suppose you've given any thought to your future career?"

"Actually... I'm not really sure what your department does."

"Yeah, the mission statement is pretty vague, but it's intentional. Originally 'Misuse of Muggle Artifacts' was intended to prevent wizard culture from becoming more like muggle culture. Dumbledore couldn't get rid of the department entirely, so he changed it to be about preventing wizards from making magical objects that muggles might stumble across."

"And you have staff?"

"Not... currently. When I need help with something important, I've been able to get a few aurors on temporary assignment. Assuming the DMLE isn't busy... Anyway, I also heard you have a... radio working at Hogwarts? So muggle studies can listen to actual muggle news reports and such?"

"Yeah, it's just a simple crystal radio. It picks up strong AM broadcasts. Though if a calculator works here, you can probably use a normal AM/FM radio, or even a TV. That will pick up a lot more stations."

Arthur looked at him with blank expression.

Harry clarified, "Just get some muggle money from Gringotts and buy stuff in London."

Arthur nodded, then exclaimed, "Oh, I think you wanted to see my calculator. This thing is a life save when I have to do accounting." Arthur frowned.

Harry leaned forward and saw that the calculator was not functioning. He retrieved his own, with the same result. He was disappointed, but not particularly surprised by this result.

Arthur shrugged, "Sometimes it doesn't work here. I don't know why, but it usually fixes itself within a week or so. Almost always works at home, though, so if you want we can try there."

"Perhaps another time. I do have classes to attend."

"A new bright star mysteriously appeared? You'd think we'd have read about that in the news", Terry smirked.

Luna explained patiently, "It didn't just appear; it's been there for years. It's just not there during astronomy class. Or whenever I look at the sky above Hogwarts. Maybe there's a ward here to hide it for some reason."

Hermione suggested, "Astronomical objects bright enough to be seen without magic or technology have been pretty well mapped for centuries. Maybe you saw a plane or a satellite? Though I'm not sure why you'd always see them in Gemini"

Terry exclaimed, "That's what I'm saying. A mystery star is crazy."

Ginny looked up, "Who appointed you arbiter of sanity?"

Terry rolled his eyes, "This is the Ravenclaw table. Go eat dinner with the other Gryffindors."

Ginny smirked, "Who put you in charge of assigning seats?"

Hermione shrugged, "Anyway, I have to get back to work on something." She got up and left.

Without turning her head, Luna's expression had changed and it was clear she was no longer following the conversation.

Harry sat down/partially collapsed into a seat nearby and began absently piling food onto a plate.

"Hey Harry?", Harry looked up from the plate. Terry continued, "How would you explain it if someone claimed they saw a really bright star that no one else knows about and isn't always there?"

Harry shrugged and returned to gathering food, "Venus and Jupiter are the brightest objects in the night sky, and I've read that they're frequently misidentified by people who don't pay much attention to the sky. And planets change position relative to the stars; it's actually how they were named. Why?"

Terry smirked at Luna, "No reason."

A group of Slytherins had Neville surrounded and disarmed. Peregrine Derrick laughed then cast hover charm, "How high do you guys think he'll bounce?"

Across the Great Hall, Harry sighed and rhetorically asked the nearby Ravenclaws, "Do any of you ever think of something you *know* is a bad idea, but it's just so awesome that you have to go through with it anyway?"

Padma frowned, "No. Knowing something is a bad idea is what happens before the decisions you don't make."

Harry nodded, removing his glasses and casting luminos onto both lenses, "Solid point."

Luna smiled, "If I didn't act on bad ideas, I'd never get anything done."

Harry chuckled, "Interesting perspective". He replaced his glasses, tapped them with his wand and muttered a sticking charm.

Anthony shook his head, "There might be a reason for that. What exactly are you planning Harry..."

Harry wasn't paying attention then because he was already in the air. A wave of silence spread out around him.

At the Slytherin table, Lesath gasped, "My lord!", and fell to his knees. Those around him glanced around at each other nervously. More than a few followed Lesath's example.

Fred whispered to George, "Marauder Junior's really got us this time."

George whispered back, "Seriously. We're never going to top this one."

Padma whispered to Anthony, "Invisible broom?"

Anthony whispered back, "That's got to be it."

Derrick's voice carried easily through the quiet hall, "You think you're so great, Longbottom. I wonder, can you fly?"

Harry drifted over and put Neville's arm over his shoulder, preparing to support his weight, "I actually haven't taught him that yet. But trust me, it's on my list." He forced a maniacal laugh.

Derrick released the hover charm and cast a stupify at Harry. It reflected off of his robe and stunned Derrick.

One of the others slowly put his wand away, then raised his hands, "Lord, forgive me, please show mercy." The rest hesitated, then followed suite.

Harry snapped, "Just get out of my sight. And get that out of here." He gestured at Derrick's body.

Harry brought Neville safely to the ground, then canceled the sticking charm and red glow on his glasses, laughing (normally this time).

Ron leveled his wand at Harry, hand visibly shaking, "Drop your wand and surrender."

Harry continued laughing.

Fred and George quickly approached Ron, "Hey, put that down." "What on earth do you think you're doing?"

"He can fly. No one can do that other than Voldemort. Didn't you see his eyes glow red? What else are we supposed to believe?"

Percy stood and casually hurdled the nearby tables, bouncing up from his landing and hanging in the air looking down at Ron. "If that's all it takes, you can address me as Dark Lord Weasley."

Fred and George laughed, allowing themselves to fall to the floor and roll back and forth.

"Too much... Too much..."

"Just imagine... Percy..."

"A dark lord..."

"And Ron... the dark wizard hunter..."

"Imagine if someone made that a play..."

"We should write that... Imagine how many tickets we could sell."

Ron opened his mouth to reply, then paused. He looked around the room at the other students. Some were laughing. Others had their wands out and shields in place. Yet others were on their knees. All were staring at Harry.

McGonagall's voice blasted through the tension, "Everyone go back to your common rooms. Mr. Potter, to my office now."

McGonagall shook her head sadly, "How are you able to be so smart and yet so dumb?".

Harry sighed, "After failing to get the hospital running for so long, after... everything... I just really needed a win somewhere. Permanently ending the bullying at this school seemed like a good thing to try. I know it wasn't the most well-reasoned idea, but all I really did was hover around a bit with my glasses glowing red; how bad could it possibly turn out?"

McGonagall shook her head, "I know you've been putting a lot of pressure on yourself. Go back to your room and try to get a full night's sleep. I'm sure you'll feel better in the morning."

Harry nodded and walked to the door, whispering to himself, "Yeah, I'm sure that will happen."

And of course, it didn't.

A young Hufflepuff whose name he couldn't remember smiled brightly, "Thank you so much for walking us back to the common room, Cedric. We wouldn't have wanted to lose points getting caught out past curfew on our own."

Cedric shrugged, "It's no problem. And I'm sure no one would have a problem with the group of you being out a few minutes late. And you were coming straight from the library. Studying magic is pretty much the point of this school."

Another shuddered, "Not to mention the other people who might be out here at night."

Cedric nodded, "Yeah, that can be a problem. It's good to keep safety in numbers."

"Did you hear that?"

"No? What was it?"

"I... I'm not sure. Maybe someone breathing?"

"Only if it was really loudly and slowly."

Cedric held a finger to his lips, and listened while the group stopped talking. After a moment, he concluded, "I don't hear- Okay, I heard that."

"It sounds like there's someone nearby."

"It didn't sound like footsteps."

"No, it was more like shuffling or dragging."

"Over there! ...I saw something move down that hallway."

"Something like what?"

"I don't know, just a dark shape. But it was pretty short, not like a person or anything."

"Is someone over there?", Cedric called out.

There was no response.

"Fair warning: if you attack us, I will have to hurt you", he added.

There was no response.

"How could anything bad happen to us with Cedric around?", someone asked, attempting a casual smile.

Cedric smiled back, stoically trying to hide his nervousness.

Cedric released a breath, "Stay here. I'll check it out." He cast a light from the end of his wand and strode forward...

Chapter 22: Conclusion

Harry cast a stupify at Ginny to ensure she was unconscious. He put her wand in his pouch then searched her and found a backup wand. He partially transfigured part of the floor into handcuffs (still attached to the floor) and restrained her.

He used a hover charm to pull the diary from the basilisk's mouth, cast analytic spells until he was convinced that the venom had neutralized the magic, then put the diary into his pouch as well.

Harry tore a sheet of paper from a notebook and cast Flitwick's mapping spell with vitalis revelio. The paper exploded and fibers shot off in all directions, bouncing around corners and leaving the room. A moment later they returned equally quickly and formed a representation of the nearest few rooms. There were two red spots in the neighboring room.

When he stepped through the doorway, nothing was immediately visible. Harry brandished the elder wand and cast the most powerful finite incantatem he could manage. Hermione became visible and dropped to the ground as the transfigured chains holding her reverted. A large, bubbling cauldron also appeared on the floor nearby.

"Harry... I mean... thanks for the rescue, but you could have dispelled the disillusionment and reversed that transfiguration without cuttings my hands off." While talking, she jumped to her feet and kicked the cauldron over.

"I thought it best to make sure any booby traps were dispelled as quickly as possible." Harry stared at the smoking, pitted floor where the cauldron's contents had spilled.

Hermione, now mostly healed, reached into the cauldron and retrieved a gold egg speckled with red spots. "Fake Ginny knew about Crookshanks somehow, so when he came to rescue me, she trapped him in an acid bath. He burned up and regenerated as an egg. The egg hatched a few times but just burned up and turned back into an egg each time. And Ginny kept refilling the acid as it boiled away."

Harry started walking back toward Ginny. "That's actually a pretty smart way to neutrali- Crookshanks?"

"Yeah, I finally found a name my phoenix liked."

"Crookshanks?"

"What would you name a phoenix? Blood commando?"

Harry shrugged, "You must have really enjoyed that argument the first time if you want to have it again."

"Let's just get out of here. I don't suppose you know where my wand is?"

"Uh... yeah, I think I know where it is. I'm going to..." Harry pulled a mirror out of his pouch and opened it, "Mad-Eye, I'm in the Chamber, headed to an exit in the first floor girls' bathroom. I destroyed a horcrux, but Ginny Weasley had been possessed by it, so I need someone to guard her and take her to... wherever they treat this sort of thing. Also, Hermione is down here with me, conscious and unharmed. Harry out."

He put the mirror away, cast another stupify at Ginny, then cast a hover charm and moved toward the exit.

As they passed the potions table, Hermione stopped and looked over it. "Harry, my wand isn't here either."

"Hold on, I'm going to take Ginny upstairs. I'll be back in just a second." He hovered Ginny up the pipe and floated after her.

He set her on the ground, cast another stupify, then turned to go back down the tunnel. He was startled by Hermione standing behind him. "How did you-"

"I climbed up. Because I can do that."

"Oh." He levitated Ginny again, opened the door, and walked out into the hall.

Hermione followed him out, "Harry, stop. You've been acting distant and weird for months. What is going on?"

Harry froze for a moment. He tried to think of things that he would say to either Hermione or Voldemort pretending to be Hermione, "Well, you've been acting unusual too, you know."

"Whatever happened today doesn't count. You know that was her polyjuiced as me, right?"

"Well, yeah, Everyone noticed 'you' acting strange today. But all year you've been, well, 'distant and weird' is a good description. You've barely been around except for classes and briefly at meals; what exactly have you been doing all year?"

"I was just working on a project. And don't think I haven't noticed that you changed the subject."

"I do do that sometimes but in this case I was acting weird around you because you were acting weird. And you know most of what I've been doing: I'm always busy working on stuff, like studying various aspects of magic and/or technology, trying to get a super-hospital running smoothly, or subtly puppet-mastering the national policy of wizarding Britain."

Hermione sighed, "I don't know how you do it. All the secrets you have to keep, all the pressure you're under from the things you're trying to do, and you come downstairs every day and keep being Harry like everything is normal. It's easier for me to play normal when the other students aren't looking at me, expecting me to talk to them."

Harry tried to quickly estimate how likely it would be that Voldemort's model of Hermione would say something like that, and concluded that Voldemort could use that excuse to avoid frequent social contact but would likely prioritize keeping informed and building relationships of possible future value. "Hermione, are you... maybe, depressed?"

"No." She sighed, "Well, maybe. Who wouldn't be? I mean, how are you okay?"

"I... I'm having some problems. I have to use a few sleeping charms to get a minimum healthy amount of sleep in a night anymore." Harry sighed, "I have to keep going anyway. Everything doesn't magically reset to the way it used to be just because the good guys win. That only happens in stories. In the real world, people experience traumas that may never fully heal and have to live with consequences. I'm not immune." Harry remembered something that he had to inform Voldemort about, and could potentially end the current situation peacefully, "Actually, one of the things that's been bothering me is that I found a serious problem in Voldemort's vow for me to not end the world: Dumbledore said that the world is prophesied to end, that it's inevitable, and that humanity can only survive if I'm the one who destroys it. But Voldemort's vow only lets me take that action if you agree, so you're a single point of failure for... everything. For example, if Voldemort or someone else possessed you, you'd no longer be my trusted friend and humans are doomed to extinction."

"Harry, you're being silly. From what you told me before, he didn't specifically name me; you can discuss those things with anyone you trust and consider a friend. So basically, you need to make more friends."

Harry smiled; he hadn't thought of that and considered it virtually impossible that Voldemort would suggest such a thing. Then he frowned, "The vow includes intent, and that was clearly not Voldemort's intent. It was your death that caused the apocalyptic prophesy he was trying to prevent."

"But Voldemort's intent wasn't relevant. He wasn't a participant in the vow ritual. The death eaters didn't know about the prophecy and wouldn't have been thinking about me. So it's only on you: is that what you intended?"

"I... I'll have to think about it."

"Wait, this isn't just hypothetical is it? Do you think I'm Voldemort now?" Her voice had risen until to almost a scream for the last question.

"Yeah, we thought you were possessed by Voldemort. It seemed like the best explanation at the time for your behavior and other stuff that was happening. Also, it makes sense that he'd want a super-powered host that I would trust."

She shuddered, "Well, I guess that's something I have to look forward to." She suddenly scowled at him, and almost-yelled, "Dammit Harry, you just said that Voldemort revived me to avert a prophecy and that he revived me so he could possess me. Those can't both be true." She continued in a calmer voice, "If you assume both of those things, because they're contradictory, you can reach any conclusion by the principle of explosion. So of course you've been coming to the most ridiculously horrible conclusions you can think of."

"Well... Mad-eye also thought you were possessed. And the defense curse is at least partially responsible for anything dumb I've done this year."

"I bet Mad-eye has a list of reasons why Headmistress McGonagall is probably possessed by Voldemort. And why Hannah Abbott is probably possessed by Voldemort. There's a place where 'constant vigilance' becomes ridiculous, and I think Moody uses it as a summer home." She gave Harry a confused look, "And you are not the defense professor."

Harry smiled, "I wonder- what are the odds that two weeks ago you'd have used Ginny instead of Hannah in that statement. And it turns out that it's not a defense curse in the strictest sense; it's just set up such that the people it affects correlate extremely well with defense professors. So if you're not secretly Voldemort, what is this secret project you've been spending all your time on?"

"Harry... I've read everything the library has on unicorns and trolls. And then read other stuff based on what I learned. Because I don't know what I am anymore. I don't think I'm even human now."

"Hermione, you're being silly. You're the same person as always, you just have super-human powers now. I'm pretty sure the hospital will be giving everyone those upgrades in maybe a decade."

Hermione growled and for a second, Harry was concerned that she was literally going to hurt him, "Is this 'silly'?"

Hermione walked over to a window, and put her hand outside. Harry watched her hand turn gray, as if the blood had drained from it. She then knocked on the wall, making a distinct stone-on-stone sound.

"My skin mineralizes in sunlight now. I can't go outside anymore. I had to wait for a blizzard for it to be safe enough. I've spent half the year reading books about dark creatures, trying to find the spell Voldemort used to protect his troll from sunlight. Just so I can maybe pretend to be normal and just do things that normal people do once in a while."

"That ca... I don't understand... I know I've seen you outside during the day before."

"It started after Azkaban. At first it was just like my joints were getting stiff but it got worse and I started avoiding direct sunlight. A week later, I went to the upper levels and tried to stand in front of a west-facing window shortly before sunset. I couldn't move away until the sun was mostly below the horizon."

"Let's think about this for a few minutes."

"Do you think I haven't done that?"

Harry ignored her comment, "Why would a troll turn into stone in sunlight? There must be a reason."

"Besides 'magic'? There isn't always a reason; sometimes magic just does weird things."

"There must be reasons. We just don't know what they are."

Hermione rolled her eyes, "Maybe someone created trolls to be a weapon and wanted them to have a weakness in case they turned on him?"

"That doesn't make sense; the weakness would apply whether they were attacking hypothetical wizard's enemies or allies. And if he or she was using magic to protect them from sunlight, why not just require a spell to keep them functional regardless of the weather, like a magical dead-man switch. I think it's more likely a side-effect, like a magical allergy... Similarly, it's hard to imagine someone deliberately setting out to invent a spell that protected trolls turning to stone. It's more likely a spell used for some other purpose and troll day-walking is a side-effect."

"Maybe you're right, but I'm not sure how to search the library for spells that have a side-effect no one else cares about."

"You mentioned Azkaban. If we knew exactly what triggered it, that would be a useful clue. But you were exposed to a phoenix, dementors, and who knows what other magic at around the same time. Was there anything that seemed especially... I don't know, painful or hard to deal with? Or that had a lasting effect?"

"Lots of stuff was annoying, but I think the burns from the rocket launcher lasted longer than anything else."

"That's familiar: fire and acid... What mineral is it?"

"Really? It was like four months before I ran out of better leads than that. I think it's chert."

"That's interesting..."

"It's really not. It's a relatively common rock."

"No? Doesn't chert mean flint? Like, the stuff that's really hard and therefore the material of choice for stone age tools and producing sparks to start fires? The fire connection seems like it might have some potions-magic related significance."

"Okay, that... might be interesting."

"Fire and acid..."

"Harry?"

"Why would they slow a troll's healing process?"

"How quickly can you heal when you're on fire?"

"That's kind of my point: I wouldn't. When most life is exposed to fire, cells are damaged and killed until they stop being exposed to fire. Troll healing is extremely fast compared to non-magical wound healing but it's not instant. In principle, if a fire is hot enough it should kill a troll's cells faster than it can regenerate them, and it should eventually die or even burn up completely. And if the fire isn't hot enough to kill a troll then the troll should regenerate cells more quickly than they're damaged, so the fire shouldn't do any noticeable damage. Same with acid, it should either progressively make troll-juice, or not do much at all. But that's not what happens. Instead, it just slows down the troll's healing."

"So something you believe is wrong. Namely, that... (the word hypothesis is probably being generous) you just made up."

"How does flint relate to acid?"

"Uh- it's like a type of quartz, and silicates are usually pretty acid resistant, I think. Unless it's hydrofluoric?"

"So it would actually be useful to have it over your skin if you were exposed to acid."

"Except for the obvious practical problems, you mean?"

"And I'd think pretty much any mineral would be better than skin against fire. What if it's purposeful? Like trolls transfigure a mineral layer when exposed to fire or acid to protect themselves from further damage, even though it delays their healing until the fire or acid is absent? Like a magical immune system?"

"You're about to suggest setting me on fire as an experiment, aren't you? I can tell because you still haven't given me back my wand."

"Oh, right." Harry absently retrieved two wands from his pouch and tossed them to her, "It's probably one of those. And that reminds me..." He turned and cast a stupify at Ginny.

Harry continued, "Ultraviolet light is ionizing radiation. It can damage DNA and kill cells; that's what a sunburn is. Maybe troll magic interprets a sunburn as close enough to a regular burn. An overreaction of a magical immune system analogous to an allergy."

Hermione sighed loudly, then pointed her wand at her other hand and cast incendio. "Huh. You may be right", she commented while tapping on the mineralized patch of skin that formed where the fire had impinged.

"Have you tried using the highest-powered sunscreen you can find?"

"No..."

"Or, there's probably a relatively common charm wizards use instead to keep from getting sunburned. That's probably what Voldemort used on the troll."

"I don't know whether to hug you or strangle you right now."

"I get that a lot. Also, as strong as you are, those really aren't mutually exclusive..."

Bones shook her head sadly, "This is all such a mess."

Moody looked pointedly at Harry, "Let this be a lesson: the next time you defeat a Voldemort mind-clone, just kill it. Everything is simpler before the damn bureaucrats get involved."

Harry sighed, "How was I supposed to know he was telling the truth about Ginny's... mind? identity? having being destroyed? No one else who touched the diary suffered permanent harm."

Moody continued staring at Harry, "We don't know that for sure. I believe I broke Ginny's occlumency barrier. I determined that she found the diary while snooping in her brother Ronald's room. After interrogating him, I concluded that someone passed it to him, but it ended up in a junk pile under his bed apparently without him having touched it or payed much attention to it at all. But he did have some memories of having seen it so at least that much of what I got from Ginny is likely to be true. So the likely explanation is that the diary passed from Lucius to Draco to Tracey to Daphne to Lavender to Ron to Ginny, but there's no way to be sure no one else was affected."

Hermione added, "I've been talking to students about what they saw. Lots of people remember Ginny having the diary, and carrying it with her regularly, since January. No one remembers seeing Draco with it at all, so he must have only used it when he was alone and had much less exposure than Ginny. The others only had the diary for a few hours. There wasn't time for what happened to her to have happened to anyone else."

Moody frowned at Hermione, "You're assuming duration is the only factor that's important."

McGonagall asked, "Isn't there some way to keep Ginny in DMLE custody until... I don't know, until someone decides she's safe to be around people?"

Bones groaned, "Her parents found out that she was at St. Mungo's and went to see her. Preventing a ministry department head from removing his child from custody when said child hasn't been formally accused of anything is... to be blunt, the first unanimous Wizengamot vote in history would be to remove the acting head Warlock."

McGonagall countered, "But she killed people."

Bones sighed, "Legally, a basilisk killed people. We can't prove she created the basilisk, we can't prove that she controlled it, and even if she did, she was under the control of the diary at the time and can't be held responsible. All you can do is... be vigilant. Get some evidence of her doing something wrong so we can do something about it."

Moody added, "Or, you know, just handle the situation before witnesses show up next time. It's a lot easier for the government to conveniently ignore lots of evidence than to do something without a mountain of paperwork."

Harry asked, "About the basilisk... why did Ginny/Riddle create one? What was the plan?"

"It was one of the most ridiculous plans I've ever heard. It's part of why I'm suspicious that she may have only pretended that her occlumency barrier failed. But if my information is correct, she was trying to create a horcrux for Slytherin's basilisk by hatching and sacrificing her own basilisk. Because she believed Slytherin's basilisk would share Interdicted spells with her. She had no idea whether it's possible to create a horcrux for a basilisk, to use the death of a basilisk to create a horcrux, to create a horcrux for an already dead body, to revive a dead body using a horcrux rather than possessing a live person, or even if all of that worked, whether the result would retain Interdicted information it had died with. She was trying to figure out how it would all work, but rushed ahead after her basilisk escaped and killed those students."

Harry exhaled slowly, "I believe Slytherin's basilisk is where Voldemort got much of his knowledge of Interdicted magic. I've been thinking about reviving it myself. Even after being dead for decades, it hasn't decomposed, so basilisks must be so toxic that even bacteria and fungi can't survive on them. Therefore its brain may still be intact. And I'm a parselmouth, so the danger of it killing anyone is negligible."

Everyone shouted variants of, "no, that's crazy."

Hermione added, "Harry, don't start creating new monsters. We already have enough problems to deal with."

Harry conceded, "Fine, I'll wait to bring it up again until we have fewer problems. Or an urgent need to learn Interdicted spells."

After a pause, McGonagall asked, "What about Lockhart? Was he kissed by a dementor, or can the healers do something to help him?"

"They can't help him. He never had liquid luck. He inherited an unregistered time-turner a few years ago. He'd been using it so he could invisibly watch dangerous situations first, then go back and act. So he always knew what was coming, what he had to do, and what he could get away with. And, understandably, he considered being Hogwarts defense professor dangerous, so he tried not to stay in the castle for more than six hours at a time. And if he hadn't spent an extra six hours in Brazil, he may have been able to use the same trick to avoid getting possessed."

Harry nodded, "That explains a lot. I wonder if everyone who claims to be able to brew 'liquid luck' is just covering up a secret time turner, like an advanced model spimster wicket."

Bones questioned, "And what happened to that horcrux?"

Moody sighed, "It flew away. Literally. Voldie drove Lockhart to the tower with the owls. He handed the Hufflepuff Cup to an owl and it took off. Lockhart was free from Voldie, but not from time. The last thing he'd seen before time-turning was a dementor advancing on his future self. He was compelled to walk into our trap, thinking he was going to die. He has a serious case of temporal psychosis. Really, what's surprising is that he didn't go nuts earlier with the way he was playing with time."

"So we'll add the Hufflepuff Cup to the ever-growing list of artifacts we have to track down. And presumably someone has obliviated Lockhart of Voldemort's memories?"

"That won't help temporal psychosis. And the cup doesn't seem to overwrite memories like the diary. It just takes over, leaving the victim aware of what's happening but unable to do anything about it."

Harry added, "That implies that the Cup is Voldemort's new type of horcrux. The diary was clearly the original type, presumably made while Riddle was still was a student. And that implies that Voldemort wasn't really obliviated, and you guys can destroy this-", Harry removed a ring and sat it on the table, "-at your convenience. His horcrux network has some defense against obliviation, either blocking that spell from traveling through the network, or leaving a backup occasionally in case something defeated the network. He would have been careful enough to leave such a backup before that night last year, and probably would have left it with Bellatrix. The bottom line is that Voldemort is still out there."

Moody nodded and picked up the ring.

Hermione asked, "Harry, you seem to be making a distinction between Voldemort and Tom Riddle. Aren't they the same person?"

Harry laughed humorlessly, "Yeah. By the way, you can probably take Ravenclaw's Diadem off your list of artifacts. I'm pretty sure I know what happened to it."

Bones looked surprised, "You know where it is?"

"Not exactly. If I had to guess, I'd say either the bottom of the ocean or deep underground. Or deep under the bottom of the ocean."

"That's not particularly helpful. Unless you think that means Voldemort will never get it?"

"I know I haven't actually interacted with young Tom Riddle, because it was always some Riddle personality merged with some of his host's personality, But there was enough of a pattern. Voldemort made a few comments about how he was stupid when he was younger and I had assumed he was talking about the standard process of learning and gathering experience that people do as they age, but after meeting his younger self, I realized it's something else. He was needlessly violent, had no self-control, spent little time planning, and was just... dumber. I think Draco-Riddle was significantly smarter than Ginny-Riddle, enough that I think Draco is smarter than original Tom Riddle was. And also, Voldemort once claimed that adding the resurrection stone to his horcrux network would allow him to possess people without requiring them to touch a horcrux. Either it didn't work out for him or he wants us to believe it didn't work, but the point is that his new horcrux spell allows him to use the magic of the objects he horcruxes.

"Therefore, I think Riddle found Ravenclaw's Diadem. And rather than just putting a standard horcrux (which would overwrite anyone who tried to use it) he decided to use it for himself. He wanted to be truly immortal, and found the old horcrux spell inadequate because of the merging effect and the loss of Interdicted knowledge. And he would've wanted to find a way to ensure he'd always be able to use the Diadem. The advanced horcrux spell he invented solved both problems: he was permanently linked to his new horcruxen so they updated their copy of his memories and kept his consciousness alive, and by making the Diadem a horcrux, he remained permanently linked to it as well. We don't urgently have to keep it away from him because he's effectively never taken it off. And that's why I make a distinction between pre-Diadem Tom Riddle and post-Diadem Dark Lord Voldemort. This year the later operated invisibly, mostly planting remote sensing devices to watch us, while the former was actively trying to obtain power and become Voldemort."

Hermione looked concerned, "Um, Harry, what about you? Does that mean we can't kill Voldemort without you getting dumber? And being unable to do world-saving stuff?"

"I've never been linked to the horcrux network. He created a basic horcrux on me while he was linked to the Diadem. I believe I got a permanent copy of that effect: just like a portrait of a confunded person stays confunded, a horcrux of a Diadem-using person retains that ability."

Moody asked, "Isn't that academic? You don't have a way to actually find and destroy all of his horcruxen, right?"

Harry started casting privacy spells. After 15, he asked Moody to cast as many more as possible. While Moody complied, Harry cast the wide-area confundus detector.

After he was satisfied that everything was safe, Harry replied, "I think Luna can find them. I don't think Voldemort knows that or she wouldn't still be alive."

Hermione sighed, "Not this again. Harry, she's not a seer. She's said some things that were surprising or coincidental, that's all."

Harry shook his head, "You're half-right. She was never a seer, but she has a sense we don't. I suspect that her mother died trying to remove a horcrux spell from something, and it resulted in Luna being able to see through the horcrux network. Everything she's seen or known is something she could've seen through a horcrux or something Voldemort would've been spying on himself."

"And what evidence do you have for that?"

"I'll admit it's mostly circumstantial..."

Hermione nodded and smiled.

"Except for one thing..."

Her smile faded.

"I got some of the details that I didn't hear originally about her mystery star that can't be seen in the Hogwarts' night sky. It's the sun... as seen from Pioneer 11."

As they walked down another flight of stairs, Harry glanced out the window. "Why is it snowing outside? It's June!"

Moody smirked, "You're asking me? I was going to ask for your theory."

"Fair enough. I wonder what would happen if I flew outside and looked back at the castle."

"I don't know but I'd recommend against it. Is this the highest you've ever been in Hogwarts?"

"Probably. I can't see the ground anymore through the snow, so this is probably high enough. Let's set up on this floor. Fawkes?"

The phoenix cawed and burned away. He quickly returned with a few of the healers Moody had recruited. A second later, Crookshanks arrived with Hermione and the rest of the healers.

"So no problems getting here, I take it?", Harry asked Hermione.

She shook her head, "I don't know how it works, but they can either follow each other or communicate a destination somehow."

Harry addressed the healers, "I'm going to teach you all a new healing spell today-"

Someone interrupted him, "Mad-eye, did you bring us here to be lectured by a ten-year-old?"

Moody scoffed, "I brought you here because this place is now more secure than Azkaban ever was. Phoenix travel is the only way in, and phoenix or portkey are the only ways out. I'm thinking that time here isn't even synchronized with the rest of the world. Anyway, have fun." He triggered a portkey and was teleported back to the empty hospital front at the edge of the Hogwarts grounds.

Harry continued, "I probably should have asked earlier; can any of you cast a patronus?"

They looked at him skeptically, but shook their heads.

"I'm not surprised."

"What's that supposed to mean? You don't think healers can be good or happy people?"

"Nothing like that; let's go over the wand movements..."

A short time later, Harry was satisfied, "Everything I'm about to tell you is covered under your non-disclosure oaths. Dementors are a magical representation of death and animal patroni represent a kind of immunity-by-ignorance to the fear of death. Healers are regularly confronted with death, so it doesn't surprise me that you can't just forget about it with happy thoughts. There is a stronger patronus charm which is powered not by hiding from death but by defiantly confronting it, and that's the form you will all need to learn."

The healers appeared skeptical, but they were listening carefully. Harry un-transfigured a stretcher, then took a coin from his pouch, placed it on the stretcher and un-transfigured it as well. It was Cedric's corpse.

The healers stepped forward, casting analytic charms. One stated the obvious, "He's dead."

Harry continued, "Yeah, a basilisk killed several students this week... The mission of this hospital isn't merely to heal the sick and injured. It's not even to heal people who can't be healed anywhere else. Its mission is nothing less than to defeat death. We aren't done until no one dies ever again. So we're going to revive them. Pay close attention; I suspect this moment will be your patronus-powering-happy-thought for the near future."

Harry got into the patronus charm starting stance. Fawkes flew over, perched on his left shoulder, and screeched confidently. Harry moved his wand, then shouted, "Expecto patronum!". Cedric lit up from inside. Harry could feel... life flow from Fawkes through himself and into his wand.

Again, the healers stepped forward.

"He's breathing."

"His heart rate is 50 beats per minute and climbing."

"His internal temperature is rising fast."

Harry interrupted, "We have 5 more students and even more aurors from Bellatrix's attack. We may not be able to revive all of them... today. But it's a step forward."

The esteemed members of the Wizengamot were bickering as usual.

"An institution that exists solely to help people, healed dozens of presumed-dead aurors, and you want to destroy it with bureaucracy. What the hell is wrong with you?", Ogden demanded angrily.

Umbridge smiled, "With all due respect, I don't think you realize how improper it is to have an organization that powerful working independently of the Ministry. Would they even obey the orders of the Wizengamot? Other countries are starting to contact them. It's undermining our foreign policy."

"I never thought I'd see the day", Harry began. "I've mostly only read about you, of course, but it's a day for the history books when you and the Goblin Nation are on the same side of an issue. People may expect a kid like me to be afraid of a goblin army, but I thought you'd be all 'let them come, we've put down rebellions before and will do it as often as they make us.'"

Umbridge turned toward him and sputtered for a few seconds.

Harry began again "Or is it something else? Would you support the hospital if they were willing to fix that human-toad thing you've been cursed with?"

A large portion of the Wizengamot, an organization known for its pretense of dignity and solemnity, erupted in a very undignified laughing fit.

As the laughter died down, Harry spoke again, "Weren't we going to talk about werewolves today?"

Someone nearby replied, "Oh, no. That was just added to the schedule a few days ago. We won't get to it for weeks."

Someone else added, "We should really talk about the goblins. We need to find out what they have against a wizard hospital and then decide how many of them we have to kill to make a point..."

Harry had a flash of regret, not for the first time, that he hadn't cleaned out the governing body with a dementor when he'd had the chance.

"Harry! I was hoping I'd find you after the Wizengamot meeting was finished."

Harry's thoughts could best be summarized as a resigned, "Oh, crap." It was Arthur Weasley. Harry turned to face him.

Arthur continued, "Thank you so much for saving my daughter. If there's anything I can do for you, don't hesitate to ask."

"Um... I was told that I was too late..."

"Nonsense. I know my daughter. She's been through a lot but she's already mostly back to her old self. All she needed was some time back with her family."

Harry attempted to find an expression more appropriate than a blank stare, but was unable to think of anything appropriate other than 'totally horrified'.

Arthur continued, "In fact, I think you should come back to my house to dinner to meet my family. I mean, you know most of us already, so I guess, just meet Molly. And I have lots of muggle artifacts that I'm sure you'll find interesting. I insist!"

After more time during which Arthur said irrelevant things and Harry was unable to tell the man he was harboring a monster in his home, Harry found himself flooing to the Weasley home.

Ron scowled at Harry, "What's he doing here?"

"Manners, Ron!" Arthur chastised. "Where's your mother?"

Ron shrugged, "Everyone else went... I don't remember. It wasn't Diagon Alley or Hogsmeade. They would have been fun."

Arthur pulled a calculator from his robes and began tapping at it. "Oh, Harry, I'm so sorry. It's not working. I swear this hasn't not worked here in years. Not since my son Bill still lived here."

Ron frowned, "I remember that summer. Bill didn't play with us at all because of that arithmancy tutor. He spent the whole summer at the kitchen table doing homework so he could take the second year arithmancy elective with his friends. And you spent the whole summer complaining about things not working."

Harry looked down at his pouch, "I do have an arithmancy book with me. Maybe it matters."

Arthur shrugged, "Try putting it in Bill's room, and we'll see what happens."

As Harry walked to the stairs, Ron got up and followed him, quietly warning, "You'd better not try anything. I'm onto you." Harry rolled his eyes.

As they reached the second landing, Arthur called, "It works now!"

Harry set the pouch on the stairs, and he and Ron began descending again. Arthur called out, "now it's off again."

Harry backtracked and Ron followed.

Harry thought for a moment. "Ron, walk about halfway down the stairs. We have to determine if it's you or me or both."

Ron scowled, "Of course it's you." But he turned and took a few steps down. While his back was turned, Harry pulled the Elder Wand out of his robes and put it into the pouch.

Ron called, "Dad, it's still working, right?"

"Yes."

Ron turned back to Harry, "Told you."

Harry shrugged and walked toward him, "How about now?"

"It's still on."

Harry pushed past Ron and ran back to the kitchen. He typed a calculation into the device to confirm the result and exclaimed, "This is big! What's the fastest way to the ministry?" He ran back up the stairs to retrieve his pouch.

Arthur asked, "I don't... You want to talk to Minister Fudge? I don't know if this is something he'd be interested in, but I could introduce you..."

While running back, Harry replied, "No, I have to tell Chief Warlock Bones about this."

"You requested an urgent meeting, Mr. Potter?", Bones asked, not bothering to hide her annoyance.

"We just made an important discovery. You know how muggle technology doesn't work at Hogwarts?"

"Yes, and I know how obsessed you are with that stuff-"

"It's not all magic; technology only seems to be affected by objects and texts covered by Merlin's Interdict!"

"Oh...", Bones straightened in her chair, giving them her full attention. "So muggle devices can be used to determine whether something is genuinely Interdicted or a forgery? Or determine if something valuable is nearby?" Harry had started nodding while Bone was talking. She continued, "How close do they have to get? Is it the same for all muggle devices? Is there a way to include a point-me spell?"

"Those are questions that it would be a very good idea to find answers for. I suspect some things, like cameras with telephoto lenses or laser range-finders or parabolic microphones may experience a directional effect at longer ranges, but that will require some-"

"Right. Mr. Weasley, I'm going to have Fudge assign additional personnel to your department to take over... your department's usual functions, so you can make this your highest priority. Do you understand what's required of you?"

Arthur stared forward, his mouth opening and closing as he struggled for a sentence.

After a pause, Bones continued, "Well, feel free to address any questions to Mr. Potter. And make an appointment as soon as you have something the aurors or unspeakables can field test." After another pause, she added, "Was there anything else?"

Arthur shook his head and backed out the door. Harry met Bones' eyes and inclined his head slightly.

Outside the office, Arthur still had a slight deer-in-headlights look. Ron inquired, "What happened in there?"

"Uh, I'm not totally sure, but I think I got promoted."

Inside the office, Bones stared at Harry, "What else do you need, Mr. Potter?"

"I know you've studied a lot of old texts looking for forgotten magic. I assume you're familiar with the pattern of spells having a second and more powerful hidden version?"

Bones nodded slowly, "I'd ask how you know that, but I suppose it's one of those many things Voldemort managed to tell you during those brief hours you were with him?"

"Have you ever heard of a second level fidelius charm? A confundus that, rather than hiding a specific, relatively small area from detection, can hide information? For example, the instructions to a spell? And is powerful enough to cover the whole world?"

Bones smiled slightly, "The first person wise enough to discover such a spell would likely use it to hide knowledge of itself. What would be written down?" Her smile faded and her eyes widened, "You think it was Merlin. A higher level fidelius that blurs information unless a secret keeper gives one the secret. One living mind to another. It does fit."

"If someone tries to use a spell to copy an Interdicted text, is it copied, or does the spell fail to produce anything useful?"

"There are spells that can copy Interdicted texts, but both texts remain Interdicted."

"Does it matter whether the person casting the copying spell has the secret or not?"

"At the DMLE, I've seen copies of things in evidence that I could read and know that the aurors who made the copies could not. It's not a transfer of information to a living mind."

"Merlin knew. That's the only explanation. The disruption of technology isn't an accident or side-effect of something else. It's a deliberate part of Merlin's Interdict. That makes the pattern obvious: only technology capable of storing or transmitting information is affected in order to prevent it from storing or transmitting Interdicted information. That's why I could transfigure working calculator circuits but a commercial calculator didn't work: I made a calculator that used combinatorial logic while everyone else makes sequential logic calculators. You type a number and it has to store it while you type another number. It explains why radio receivers work but not transmitters. Centuries earlier than everyone else, Merlin knew that muggles would develop technology that could break his Interdict unless he took steps to prevent it."

Harry's face took on a look of determination, "I don't know how to break the Interdict of Merlin, but for the first time, I know something about what that solution will look like."